愤怒的公牛
纽约市 1964年
夜访杰克拉莫塔
我记得那些欢呼声
I remember those cheers,
至今仍在耳边回响
they still ring in my ears,
多年来仍不时想到它们
and for years they remain in my thoughts,
有一天晚上
'cause one night,
我脱掉我的外袍,结果呢?
I took off my robe, and what'd I do?
我忘了穿上短裤
I forgot to wear shorts.
我记得每一次跌倒 每一个勾拳和直拳
I recall every fall, every hook, every jab,
还有最糟的减肥方法
the worst way a guy can get rid of his flab,
你知道我的人生并不平淡
as you know, my life wasn't drab.
不过我宁愿...
Though I'd much...
我宁愿听你们欢呼...
Though I'd rather hear you cheer when you delve...
我宁愿你们是因为 听我演莎士比亚而欢呼...
Though I'd rather hear you cheer when I delve into Shakespeare...
“马儿!马儿! 一匹马毁了我的王国!”
"A horse! A horse! My kingdom for a horse!"
我有六个月没赢了
I haven't had a winner in six months.
虽然我不是奥立维,我宁愿...
And though I'm no Olivier, I would much rather...
虽然我不是奥立维 如果他跟罗宾森对打的话
And though I'm no Olivier, if he fought Sugar Ray,
他会说重点不是比赛,而是娱乐
he would say that the thing ain't the ring, it's the play.
让我这只公牛 有个可以发威的舞台吧
So, give me a stage where this bull here can rage,
虽然我可以打斗,我宁愿吟诵
and though I can fight, I'd much rather recite.
那才是娱乐
That's entertainment.
杰克拉莫塔 1964年
-杰克拉莫塔,1941年 -那才是娱乐
That's entertainment.
杰克拉莫塔和吉米里维
Jake La Motta and Jimmy Reeves
在克利夫兰体育场
in the Cleveland Arena.
拉莫塔还没被击倒 但是得分落后很多
La Motta is undefeated, but he's well behind on points.
布朗克斯公牛在这一局挨了不少拳
The Bronx Bull has taken a lot of punishment in this bout.
杰克的左眼受伤 吉米里维略胜...
Jake is cut around the left eye. Jimmy Reeves has outboxed him...
杰克,告诉我 我们它妈的干嘛跑来克利夫兰
Jack, tell me, why the fuck do we have to come to Cleveland for you
看你被小打败?
to get beaten by a mulignane?
拜托,它妈的振作起来吧
Come on, do the fuckin' right thing.
他吃定你了,你得分落后
He's got you by the balls, you're outpointed.
你要在第十局领先 你得把他打倒在地
You're comin' up for the tenth, you're gonna have to knock him out.
我要你咬他,踢他,不择手段
I want you to bite him, kick him, do anything you gotta do.
没人会看到,你知道怎么做
Nobody's lookin', you know what to do.
和在家乡一样...痛扁那些王八蛋
Just like home... all over the fuckin' moolies.
把那混蛋打倒 听懂没?把他打倒
Knock the motherfucker out. You understand? Knock him out.
你想上场吗? 你想上场去打吗?
Hey, you wanna go in there? You wanna go in and do it?
救命!
Help!
咱们上场去把他打倒吧
We need a knockout, let's go get a knockout,
上场去吧
that's where it's at.
第十局,最后一局 祝你们好运
Tenth and final round. Good luck to you both.
拉莫塔位居下风
La Motta fighting out of a halfcrouch.
里维面对难缠的对手
Reeves is up against a tough fighter,
一个绝不打退堂鼓的人
a man who doesn't know how to back up.
拉莫塔持续进攻 说时迟哪时快
La Motta continues to bore in, out of the bob and weave,
左勾拳打到下巴 里维倒地了!
hooks a left hand to the jaw, and Reeves is down!
观众在为杰克加油
The crowd is urging Jake on.
裁判在为里维计时 他得快爬起来
The referee is tolling over Reeves. He's got to get up.
拉莫塔再度进攻 里维的右拳没打中
La Motta comes at him once again, Reeves misses a right,
吃了两记左拳 一记重重的左拳打中下巴
takes a left, and another left, a hard left hand to the jaw,
里维二度倒地
and Reeves is down for the second time.
意志坚定的杰克拉莫塔在第十局
A determined Jake La Motta is making a great comeback
漂亮地抢回优势
here in the tenth round.
里维又爬起来,拉莫塔进攻
Reeves is up again, La Motta comes at him.
下巴一记左勾拳 又一记左拳,右拳打中身体
Aleft hook to the jaw, another left, and a right to the body.
三个左拳打中上半身 下巴一记勾拳
Three more lefts to the midsection, a hook on the jaw,
头部又两记左拳 下巴一记右拳又一记左拳
two more lefts to the head, a right and a left to the jaw.
里维第三度倒地
Reeves goes down for the third time,
裁判把拉莫塔拉走
and the referee is pulling La Motta away.
二...三...
Two... three...
四...五...
four... five...
-裁判在为里维计时 -六...七...
- The referee is counting over Reeves, - six... seven...
-但是时间不多了 -八...九...
- but time is running out... - eight... nine...
铃响了
...and there is the bell.
动弹不得的里维被铃声解救
He can't walk, but Reeves has been saved by the bell.
但拉莫塔会不会动作慢了点?
But did La Motta do it soon enough?
杰克,杰克,过来
Jack, Jack, come here.
这样不行 这里是俄亥俄,不是纽约!
It's no good. This is Ohio, not New York!
-你等得太久了! -那个笨蛋!
- You waited too long! - That dumb bastard!
把袍子穿好 把我的袍子穿好!
Put the robe on right, huh? Put my robe on right!
各位女士先生...
Ladies and gentlemen...
根据俄亥俄拳击委员会的规定
...under the rules of the Ohio Boxing Commission,
一致决定
after ten rounds,
这十局比赛的获胜者是
the winner, by unanimous decision,
-吉米里维! -精彩的杰克拉莫塔
- Jimmy Reeves! - The colorful Jake La Motta,
布朗克斯公牛输了第一场比赛
the Bronx Bull, has lost his first fight.
是杰克赢了比赛! 拜托,杰克赢了比赛!
That's Jake's fight! Come on, that's Jake's fight!
是杰克赢了那场比赛!
Jake won that fight!
不要走,不要下场,待在这儿
Don't leave. Don't get outta the fuckin' ring. Stay here.
你赢了...让他先走 你给我留下来
You won... let him go first. Stay in, I'm tellin' you.
拉莫塔在比赛中打倒里维七次
La Motta floored Reeves seven times in the fight,
但是拉莫塔居然输了比赛
but La Motta still lost the fight.
杰克!杰克!杰克!杰克!
Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake!
救命啊!
Help!
纽约市布朗克斯区 1941年
...他躺在地上 他们把他抬走,他不醒人事
...on his fuckin' back, they pick up his arm, he's dead.
他们说他赢了比赛,观众抓狂了
They tell him he won the fight. People went crazy.
如果有汤米照应 就不会发生那种鸟事
That shit woulda never happened if Tommy was there takin' care of it.
他在纽约比赛 要听汤米的话才能打进冠军赛
He's gotta be with Tommy to fight in New York, to get a title shot.
你哥哥会变成酒鬼
He's gonna wind up punch-drunk, your brother.
-我知道 -你知道
- I know. - You know.
你得让他明白这样对大家都好
You gotta make him understand it's the best thing for everybody involved.
-我说我知道 -你知道
- I said I know. - You know,
可是你得让他知道,让他明白
but you gotta make him know, make him understand it.
老天,你要不要住口?
Jesus Christ, you wanna stop?
你何时才会它妈的停止?
When the fuck you gonna stop with that stuff?
我跟你说过我都明白
I told ya, I understand everything.
他只会为自己着想
He just wants to do things for himself.
-听不懂吗? -那是因为他是
- Hard to understand? - It's because he's got a head
-死脑筋 -你很好笑耶
- like concrete. - You make me laugh.
你以为很容易? 你怎么不去跟他说?
You think it's easy? Why don't you talk to him?
-你知道要说什么 -你知道我没办法和他说话
- You know what to say. - You know I can't talk to him.
-为什么不行? -因为他不喜欢我
- Why can't you talk to him? - 'Cause he don't like me.
没人喜欢你,你应该习惯了
Nobody likes you, you oughta be used to it.
大家知道
They knew.
大家知道谁赢了
They knew who was the boss.
裁判不知道 谁知道这些人是怎么回事?
The judges didn't know. Who knows what happened with them?
观众知道
The people knew.
你不相信我 你以为我在那儿胡搞吗?
You don't believe me, you thought I was over there foolin' around, huh?
你以为我在胡搞对不对? 告诉我实话
You thought I was foolin' around, didn't ya? Tell me the truth.
我可不是胡搞瞎搞
I ain't doin' no foolin' around.
-是你这么想 -是又怎么样?
- That's in your mind. - Yeah, so what?
等我戴上冠军腰带 我才会开始胡搞
That championship belt on me, that's when I fool around.
熟了没?
Is it done?
还没熟
No, it's not done.
不要煎太老 煎太老就不好吃了
Don't overcook it. You overcook it, it's no good.
它就失去意义了
It defeats its own purpose.
你在做什么? 我说了不要煎太老
What are you doin'? I just said don't overcook it.
你把它煎老了,拿过来呀
You're overcookin' it, bring it over.
-你要你的牛排吗? -拿过来呀
- You want your steak? - Bring it over.
拿过来!
Bring it over!
快变成木炭了!拿过来!
It's like a piece of charcoal! Bring it over here!
-你要你的牛排? -对,现在就要!
- You want your steak? - Yeah, right now!
好,你的臭牛排
Good. There's your stupid steak.
-等不及把它煎熟是吧? -对,我等不及了
- Can't wait for it to be done? - No, I can't wait.
好,可以了吗?高兴了吗?
Good. Okay? Happy?
-高兴了吗? -我只要这个
- Happy? - That's all I want.
拿去,没有了,都拿去
That's... there, no, more. There.
你为了牛排跟我吵? 你为了牛排跟我吵?
Botherin' me about a steak, huh? You're botherin' me about a steak?!
我同意,他应该听汤米的
I agree with you. He should be with Tommy.
他如果心情好,我会跟他说 不然你要我怎么样?
If he's in a good mood, I'll talk to him. What the fuck you want me to do?
汤米每天都要我来找你
Tommy tells me every day to talk to you
去跟杰克谈,解决这件事
and speak to Jake to straighten this thing out,
到头来我会两面不是人
I'm gonna wind up in the middle.
你两面不是人?我是他弟弟
You're in the middle? I'm his brother.
-他把我搞疯了 -你是他弟弟
- He's got me fuckin' nuts. - You're his brother.
如果你不能跟他谈,谁能跟他谈?
If you can't talk to him, who's gonna talk to him?
-我会跟他谈 -你尽力就好
- I'll talk to him. - Do what you can, that's all.
-我只求这么多 -明天见
- That's all I'm askin' you. - I'll see you tomorrow.
-让我上去 -好吗?你会在哪儿?
- Let me go up. - All right? Where you gonna be?
我会在体育馆或其它的老地方
I'll be at the gym or the other joint, one of the two.
-我会去体育馆找你 -好,沙维?
- I'll catch you by the gym. - All right. Sal?
-怎么? -去死吧
Yeah?
再抱怨啊,我要听听
Complain some more, I wanna hear.
-抱怨?这是胡萝卜吗? -没错
- Complain? You call those carrots? - That's right.
-这算是食物吗? -你吃啦,你有没有吃?
- You call that food? - You ate 'em. Did you eat them?
这算是食物吗?我没有选择啊!
You call that food? I got no choice!
-我受不了你了! -我没有选择啊!
- I'm sick of you already! - I got no choice!
-我不敢相信! -我没有选择!
- I can't believe you! - I got no choice!
你没有选择?离我远一点!
You got no choice? Get away from me!
-拜托你! -给我进来,给我进来!
- Please! - Get in there. Get in there!
不要碰我,离我远一点!
Get your hands off me, get away from me!
它妈的!我受够你了!
Fuck! I'm sick of you!
在搞什么,你们是畜牲吗?
What's the matter with you, you animals?
-什么? -杰克,别这样!
- What?! - Jack, come on!
-你们是畜牲! -好了啦?
- You animals! - Come on, huh?
这只王八骂我是畜牲
This son of a bitch is callin' me an animal.
-喂! -好了,杰克
- Hey, you! - Come on, Jack.
我会把那只狗抓来当午餐吃!
I'm gonna get hold of that dog, and I'm gonna eat it for lunch!
你听到没?听到没,赖瑞?
You hear what I'm sayin'? You hear me, Larry?
-赖瑞? -发狂的畜牲!
- Larry? - Crazy animal!
谁是畜牲?你妈才是畜牲!
Who's an animal? Your mother's an animal!
你这只王八!
You son of a bitch!
你明天会在走廊上 看到那只狗的尸体
You're gonna find your dog dead in the hallway tomorrow, ya bum.
-我受不了啦! -整条街上的人
- I can't take it! - The whole block,
-都听到你们在吵 -我要把他们全家杀了
- people could hear you. - I'll kill the whole family.
-坐下,轻松点 -我再也受不了了!
- Sit down, relax. - I can't take this anymore!
你在里头打破东西,我就宰了你!
You break anything in there, I'm gonna kill ya!
我对天发誓我会进去杀了你
I swear to God, I'm gonna come in there and kill ya.
来啊
Yeah, sure.
你要冷静点吗?
You wanna calm down?
它妈的!
Oh, fuck!
我做了什么?
What'd I do?
好了,甜心,我们和好吧
Come on, honey, let's be friends.
-别吵了好吗? -不好!
- Truce, all right? - It's not all right!
我告诉你,你不能...
You can't, I'm telling you...
你不能整天暴饮暴食
you can't fuckin' eat and drink like an animal,
过着这种生活
put up with this fuckin' brasciole here.
你不能这样,我告诉你
You can't do this. I'm tellin' ya.
忘了里维那件事 你还有无数场比赛要打
Forget about the Reeves thing, you got a million other fights comin' up.
你不能这样下去
You just can't keep doin' this.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你有心事,怎么了?
Something's the matter, what's up?
你知道我在烦什么吗?
You know what's botherin' me?
我的手
My hands.
你的手?怎么样?
Your hands? What about 'em?
我的手很小,我的手是女人的手
I got these small hands. I got a little girl's hands.
我的也是,有什么差别吗?
I got 'em, too. What's the difference?
知道那代表什么吗?
Know what that means?
不管我变得多强,不管我跟谁打
No matter how big I get, no matter who I fight,
不管我怎么做 我永远都无法和乔路易斯对打
no matter what I do, I ain't never gonna fight Joe Louis.
没错,他是重量级 你是中量级的
That's right, he's a heavyweight, you're a middleweight.
我永远都没有机会 和最强的高手对决
I ain't never gonna get a chance to fight the best there is.
你知道吗?我比他们都强
And you know somethin'? I'm better than them.
我却永远没有机会
I ain't never gonna get a chance.
你还问我怎么了
You're asking me what's wrong.
你疯了才会有这种想法
You're crazy to even think about somethin' like that.
他是重量级的,你是中量级的
He's a fuckin' heavyweight, you're a middleweight.
本来就不可能发生 干嘛烦这种事?
It's impossible, it'll never happen, so why go crazy thinkin' about it?
太不正常了
It's not normal.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
-好,干嘛? -我要你打我的脸
- Yeah, what? - I want you to hit me in the face.
-什么? -我要你打我的脸
- What? - I want you to hit me in the face.
别想
Forget about it.
我要你打我的脸,快点
I want you to hit me in the face, go ahead.
-使尽最大的力气 -别想,我不要
- Take your best shot. - Forget about it, I ain't doin' it.
我们常打架...你担心什么?
We have fights all the time... are you worried now?
打我的脸,来吧
Hit me in the face. Go ahead.
-不要 -怎么,你怕吗?
- No. - What, are you afraid?
怕什么?
Afraid of what?
快点,别像娘娘腔,打我
Come on, don't be a little faggot, hit me.
-我不是娘娘腔 -使出最大的力气,快
- I ain't a fag. - Take your best shot, go ahead.
别这样,你这混蛋 竟然要我打你的脸
Come on. You gotta be a real jerk, you want me to punch you in the face.
我已经说过了 我再说一次,你非打不可
Did I not tell you just to do it? Now I'm tellin' you, you gotta do it.
我不要打你
I ain't hittin' ya.
我是你哥哥,乔伊 我在跟你说话
I'm your older brother, Joey. I'm tellin' ya somethin'.
我知道你说什么,我不要
I know what you said. I ain't doin' it.
我不管你会不会发火,我不要
I don't care if you get mad, I ain't doin' it.
它妈的疯子
Fuckin' nut.
我不要,我不要那么做
I'm not doin' it, I'm not gonna do it.
我没有手套,要我拿桌子打你吗?
I don't have any gloves. What am I gonna hit you with, the table?
-我不要 -用那个就好
- I ain't doin' it. - Use that over there.
-什么? -没错,用那个
- What? - That's right, use that.
用那个把手包起来! 你要我说几次啊?
Wrap it around your hand! How many times I gotta tell you?
-不要再说了 -来吧
- Not too many more. - Go ahead.
你要我打你?
- You want me to hit you? - I want you to hit me
我要你使出全力 我要你把我打倒在地上,来吧
with everything you got. I want you to fuckin' lay me out, go ahead.
-你确定? -对
- You sure? - Yeah.
-来吧 -好吧
- Go ahead. - All right.
-用力点 -是吗?
- Harder. - Yeah?
你的拳真娘娘腔,拜托
You throw a punch like you take it up the ass, come on.
用力点,用力点
Harder, harder.
-用力点 -我用力了,妈的
- Harder. - That's hard, you fuck.
-你想怎样? -脱下来
- What do you want? - Take it off.
-脱下来 -好了,可以住手了吗?
- Take it off. - Come on, you wanna stop now?
-够了吧... -脱下来
- That's enough with that... - Take it off.
别这样
Come on.
-来啊 -不要闹
- Come on. - Don't fuck around.
-你是女人吗? -女人是吧?
- What are you, a girl? - Oh, girl, huh?
我会再打你的,再来
I'm gonna smack you again, throw it again.
-够了 -来吧
- That's enough. - Go ahead.
-我说够了! -用力点,用力点
- I said that's enough! - Harder, harder.
不要,你的伤口又开了
No, your fuckin' cuts are opening and everything.
你想证明什么?这能证明什么?
What are you tryin' to prove? What does it prove?
嘿,维多
Hey, Vito.
乔伊,都好吗?
Joey, what's what?
杰克,气色不错哟
Jake, you're lookin' good.
你好吗?
How you doin'?
别待在这儿
Don't stay here.
乔伊
Joey.
过来
Come here.
他生气了是吧?
Yeah, he looks mad, huh?
看来在生气
Looks mad.
昨天找他谈的,不知道
Spoke to him yesterday, I don't know.
你找他们来这儿的吗?
You told 'em to come up here?
回答我的话
Answer me when I talk to you.
怎么了?我不能找朋友来吗?
Yeah, why? I can't have my friends up here?
-听说这混蛋输了比赛 -说话小心点
- I heard this fucker didn't win the fight. - Take it easy.
不准再把他们带来,听见没?
Don't ever bring 'em up here again, hear me?
听见没?说啊
Hear me? Come on.
-来啊! -他们两个看来像同性恋
- Come on! - They look like two fags over there.
我们走了,明天打电话给你
We're gonna go, I'll call you tomorrow, huh?
杰克,小心别伤到自己
Hey, Jake, watch you don't hurt yourself.
夫人好吗?一切都好吗?
How's your wife? Is everything okay?
有人找你麻烦就来找我,好吗?
Anybody bothers you, let me know, okay?
挥手啊,他们是你的朋友
Yeah. Yeah, wave. They're your friends.
你是怎么搞的? 你非让我出糗不可是吧
What the fuck is wrong with you?! You gotta make a fuckin' jerk outta me.
他们来是因为汤米 要他们来帮我们
They only came up here 'cause Tommy told 'em to come up to try to help us.
你怎么搞的,帮谁? 你是怎么搞的?
What's the matter with you, help who? What's the matter with you?
他们要怎么帮我?拿我的钱吗?
How they gonna help me? What, by takin' my money?
你们在讨论怎么拿我的钱吗?
Is that what youse talkin' about, takin' my money?
在场上卖命的是我,不是他们
I'm here breakin' my ass, not them.
不准再把他们带来这里,听到没?
Don't ever bring 'em up here again, you hear me?
你是蠢蛋吗?
What are ya, a jerk there?
我是蠢蛋? 你才是它妈的王八蛋
I'm a jerk? You're a fuckin' asshole.
你干嘛打我?
What the fuck you hittin' me, huh?!
你硬汉是吧,吃这一拳
Yeah, yeah, ya fuckin' hard-on, try this.
也许你硬不起来?
Maybe you can't, huh?
混蛋!
Ya fuck!
热狗,沙士,冰淇淋
给我一瓶可乐
Come on, give me a Coke.
走开,你们要去跳舞吗?
Hey, shove off. You gonna go to the dance?
要去跳舞吗?
Go to the dance?
-那个女孩是谁? -刚才和我说话的那个吗?
- Who's that girl over there? - The one I was talkin' to?
-对 -金发妞?
- Yeah. - The blonde?
-对 -她是维琪
- Yeah. - Vickie, you mean.
-她是哪里人? -她就住在附近
- Where's she from? - She's from the neighborhood,
她是邻家女孩
she's a neighborhood girl.
她姓什么?
What's her last name?
我只知道她叫维琪 他们都叫她维琪
Vickie, that's all I know. They call her Vickie.
她认识他们?
She knows them?
她认识他们,他们认识她 她每天都来泳池
She knows them, they know her, she comes to the pool every day.
大家都认识...你知道的
Everybody knows each other... you know how that shit works.
-她跟他们混吗? -她谁也不混
- She go with them? - She don't go with nobody.
她才十五岁,她能上哪去?
She's 15 years old, where the fuck's she gonna go?
你要带她去酒吧吗?
Where ya gonna take her, the Copacabana?
我听说他有个女友
I heard there was a girl that he went with
是个年轻的金发美女
that was a very beautiful young girl, blonde.
-怎样? -不是她吗?
- Yeah? - It's not her?
我想不太可能
I doubt it very much.
你到底在想什么?
What are you thinkin' about, anyway?
她不是那种可以 随便打一炮的女孩子
She ain't the kinda girl you just fuck and forget about.
乔伊,你要我说几次?
Joey, how many times I gotta tell ya?
你为什么老是在我面前说粗话?
Why are you always cursin' when I'm talkin' to you?
别在我面前说,去找你的朋友说
Don't do it around me. Do it around your friends.
-就是不喜欢你这么做 -好,她...
- It's that thing, just don't do it. - All right, she's...
她不是那种随便上床的女孩子
The kinda girl you bang and forget about... she's not like that.
你得花时间陪她,谈感情
You gotta spend time with her, get involved.
你知道吧...
You know, it's...
你有上她吗?
D'you bang her?
-没有 -告诉我实话
- No. - Tell me the truth.
我说的是实话 我第一次就跟你说实话了
I just told you the truth. I tell you the truth the first time,
你不必再问我一次 我就不会那样
you don't have to ask me again, I never do that.
我只跟你说实话 如果我做了,你会知道
I always tell you the truth. If I did it, you would know.
我带她出去几次
I took her out a couple of times.
你和她约会? 你没有想办法上她?
You went with her? You didn't try to fuck her?
我什么都想上,你知道的
I try to fuck anything, you know that.
-她没让你上? -没有,她不要
- She didn't go with you? - No, she didn't go for it.
-当然了 -当然?
- Naturally. - Naturally?
-算她聪明 -什么叫算她聪明?
- She knew better. - What do you mean, she knew better?
她知道你是个畜牲
She knew you were an animal,
她知道和你在一起没有好下场
she knew it was no good if you'd go with her.
她的名声会毁于一旦
Her reputation would be ruined.
他刚才和你的维琪说话
I thought he was talkin' to you, Vickie.
-那个... -同一个家伙?
- That's... - That's the same guy?
-对,同一个家伙 -我要打断他的腿
- Yeah, it's the same guy. - I gotta break his legs.
他昨天也在
He was over here yesterday.
-他昨天也在? -你错过他了
- He was here yesterday? - You missed him.
我昨天在家,不知道他在这儿
I was up to the house yesterday. Didn't know he was over here.
-你留在这儿,我去找他 -不,我会碰到他的
- You stay in there, I'll go find him. - No, I can catch him.
你的朋友在偷偷开会谈生意
Your friends, they're in a huddle. Big business meeting.
他们跑来泳池边谈话
Come by the pool, they sit around and talk.
谈大生意,故意让她听到
Big deals. They make sure she can hear.
J得不得了,滚远点吧
Hey, like the big man. Get the fuck outta here.
你要去哪,要下水吗?
Where you goin', gettin' in the water?
别把头发弄湿了
Don't get your hair wet.
大人物
Big shot.
把他拖到后头去扁一顿就知道...
Get him alone in the back room, smack him around, no more big shot...
没枪就不是大人物了
without his gun.
一副硬汉的样子
Yeah, real tough guys.
-他们都是硬汉 -你在想什么?
- They're all tough guys. - What are you thinkin' about?
还看,你在想什么? 你死会了,你结婚了
Keep lookin'. Where the fuck you goin'? You're dead, you're married.
你结婚了,没得玩了 把妹妹留给我吧
You're a married man, it's all over. Leave the young girls for me.
大人物
Big shot.
咱们快走吧 你要在这儿耗一晚吗?
Let's get outta here. You gonna stay here all night?
我们会进不去的
We'll never get through.
你这么晚了想上哪儿去?
Where the hell do you think you're goin' at this hour?
你是条子吗? 我要出去谈生意
What are you, a cop? I'm goin' out. Business.
人渣,你出去我也要出去
Fuckin' worm. You go out, I'm goin' out.
随便你,我不在乎
Do what you're gonna do, what do I care?
出去啊,我不在乎
Run out, see if I care.
你回来就看不到我了!
I'm not gonna be here when you get back!
它妈的死意大利人
Fuckin' bunch of guineas.
-走到哪儿都黏在一起! -你住嘴好不好?
- You're always hangin' out together! - Why don't you stop already?
你怎么不住嘴? 你才不是去谈生意
Why don't you fuckin' stop? You're not goin' on business.
-你们是同性恋! -你放尊重点
- You're goin' to suck each other off! - Why don't you have some respect?
-整栋楼都听到了 -让他爽!让他爽!
- The whole buildin' hears ya. - Suck him! Suck him, baby!
赖瑞!这下子你又有八卦可以说了
Hey, Larry! Now you got somethin' to talk about
那只狗加上楼上这只母狗
with that fuckin' dog, and this one up there.
死犹太婊子,你怎么不教训她?
Fuckin' Jew cunt, why don't you hit her in the head with a bat?
不准骂她,她还是我老婆
Don't call her no names, she's still my wife.
-你还要忍受多久? -我教训她了
- How much abuse you wanna take? - I hit her enough.
-我还能怎么办? -把她宰了
- What am I supposed to do? - Kill the fuck.
走啊!把我像狗一样丢在家里!
Go ahead! Just leave me here like a dog!
你们...你也一样...滚啊!
You and your fuckin' ass... you, too ya... go out!
-你是怎么回事? -你才怎么回事?
- What's the matter with you?! - What the fuck's the matter with you?
-你要把我丢在这儿? -整条街都听到你在吼
- You gotta leave me here?! - You let the whole block hear you.
-你是怎么回事? -我才不在乎,死同性恋!
- What's the matter with you?! - I could give a shit, ya fuckin' queer!
-同性恋!去搞他啊! -你说什么?
- Faggot! Go stick it up his ass! - What'd you say?!
圣克莱教堂 年度夏季舞会
八月六日星期六 切斯特饭店
哦!宾斯!
Oh! Beans!
杰克
Jack.
宾斯在后面有一桌 他说我们可以跟他们坐
Beansy got a table in the back, he said we could sit with them.
宾斯?哪个宾斯?
Beansy who? Which Beansy?
-啊? -哪个宾斯?
- Huh? - Beansy who?
宾斯,他和他们一起的
Beans, you know, he's one of the guys.
-你见到他就知道了 -她会在那边吗?
- You'll know him when you see him. - She'll be over there?
我不知道 但至少从那儿可以看得到
I don't know, but you could see from there, at least.
-咱们走吧 -我不想表现太明显
- Come on, let's go. - I don't wanna look too hard.
-乔伊,你好吗? -宾斯,你好吗?
- Hello, Joe. How you doin'? - Beansy, what is it?
谢谢你安排座位
Thanks for the seats.
-嗨,乔伊 -嘿,你怎么样?
- Hi, Joey. - Hey, what's up? Hey.
没什么,楼下有两个混球找我麻烦
Nothing. I got trouble with these two motherfuckin' greaseballs downstairs,
-快把我搞疯了 -神父,你好吗?
- they got me crazy. - Hello, Father, how ya doin'?
-神父,你好吗? -神父!
- Hey, Father, what is it? - Oh, ho, Father!
你想找人上床吗?你确定?
You wanna get laid? You sure?
-你确定? -不要,不要
- You sure? - Hey, no, no.
神父,你要上哪去? 祝福我们啊
Father, where you goin'? Bless the table, give us a shot.
你这星期有捐钱吗?
D'you put money in the basket this week?
-有没有看到她在那儿? -看到了
- You see her right there? - I saw, I saw.
-有吧? -看到了
- Okay? - I saw.
-他们在约她 -别管他们,过去吧
- They're goin' with her. - Don't worry about them, go ahead.
过去吧
Go ahead.
滚出去,你这个混蛋!
Get the fuck out, you greaseball bastard!
出去!出去!
Get out! Get out!
你也是,出去
You, too, get out.
滚出去,无赖!
Get outta here, ya fuckin' bum, ya!
-下三滥! -滚回老家去吧
- Rotten bastards! - Go back where you came from.
嘿,维琪!
Hey, Vickie!
-嗨,乔伊 -你好吗?
- Hi, Joey. - How you doin'?
-还好,你在做什么? -没什么,你呢?
- I'm all right, what are you doin'? - Nothin' much, what are you doin'?
-那是你的车吗? -不,是我哥的车
- That your car? - No, it's my brother's.
你见过我哥吗?
D'you ever meet my brother?
-没有,就是他吗? -对,想不想认识他?
- No, Is that him? - Yeah. Wanna meet him?
-好啊 -杰克!
- All right. - Hey, Jack!
来了
There.
维琪,这是我哥杰克 他是未来的冠军
Vickie, this is my brother Jake. He's gonna be the next champ.
嗨
Hi.
你好吗?
How you doin'?
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
-车子很漂亮 -你喜欢这部车?
- Nice car. - You like that car?
对,很漂亮
Yeah. It's nice.
你是哪里人?
Where you from?
住在附近
Around here.
你想去兜风吗?
You wanna go for a ride?
好啊,等我几分钟,我得换衣服
All right. Gotta give me a few minutes, I have to change, okay?
-好吗? -好
- All right? - All right.
-我马上回来 -我在那里等你
- I'll be back in a little while - I'll be over there.
好
Okay.
坐过来
Move over.
-我从来没玩过 -挥吧
- I never played this game. - Go ahead.
这样你才学得会 来,我教你怎么做
It's the only way you're gonna learn. Here, I'll show you how to do it.
就是那样,对了
That's the way, that's right.
-像这样? -对,那样
- Like this? - Yeah, that's right.
-打它吗? -打一次就好
- Hit it? - Just hit it nice.
打中间那个
Hit the middle one.
有看到吗?
You see it?
没有
No.
那代表什么?
What does that mean?
代表游戏结束了
It means the game is over.
咱们走吧
Come on, let's go.
爸爸?
Daddy?
爸? 请进
Dad? Come on in.
可能去买东西了,我看看
Probably went shoppin' or somethin', let me see.
他一定是去买东西了,请坐
Yeah, he must have went shoppin'. Sit down.
-你要吃东西吗? -不用
- You want somethin' to eat? - No.
-你确定? -嗯
- You sure? - Mm-hmm.
干杯
Salute.
你坐过来这里吧? 坐靠近一点
Why don't you sit over here? Sit a little closer.
你坐好远,好像在房间的另一头
You're so far away, like you're on the other side of the room.
过来,过来
Come here, come here.
过来,坐这里
Come here. Sit over here.
过来,坐上来
Come on, come up from there.
这样好多了
That's better.
不了,谢谢
No, thank you anyway.
要喝水吗?
Some water?
想看看环境吗?
Wanna see the rest of the place?
好
All right.
我买给我父亲的,我买了整栋楼
I bought it for my father. I bought the building.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
-靠打拳? -对
- From fightin'? - Yeah.
还能靠什么?
What else?
这里是饭厅
This is the dining room.
那儿有一只鸟
That's a bird.
以前有一只鸟,现在死了
It was a bird. It's dead now, I think.
卧房
The restroom.
坐下
Sit down.
那是我和我弟弟 我们在闹着玩
That's me and my brother. We were foolin' around.
我知道
I know.
你很帅
You look good, though.
你在笑什么?
What are you smilin' about?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道你有多美吗?
You know how beautiful you are?
有人跟你说过你很美吗?
Anybody ever tell you how beautiful you are?
大家一定常常告诉你
Yeah, they tell you all the time.
罗宾森和杰克拉莫塔在底特律
Sugar Ray Robinson and Jake La Motta in Detroit
进行第二场比赛
for their second fight.
不败的罗宾森去年十月
The undefeated Sugar Ray defeated Jake
在麦迪森广场花园打败了杰克
at Madison Square Garden last October.
你可以看出两人风格的不同
You can see the contrast in their styles...
迅速的罗宾森保持警觉 最擅长迂回战术
the speedy Ray Robinson up on his toes, the dancing master.
好斗的拉莫塔总是直接进攻
La Motta the brawler moves in flat-footed most of the time.
现在他重击罗宾森了
Now he's hurt Robinson.
拉莫塔再度进攻
La Motta coming at Robinson again,
双手击中头部 下巴一记左拳又一记右拳
both hands to the head. A left and a right to the jaw.
拉莫塔一记左拳重击对方身体
A hard left hand to the body thrown by La Motta.
第八局,目前仍胜负不明
Round 8, and it's anybody's fight at this point, 10-rounder.
拉莫塔双手击中头部 再度重击罗宾森
La Motta drives both hands to the head, hurts Robinson again.
下巴一记左勾拳,身体一记右拳
Hooks the left hand to the jaw, a right to the body.
罗宾森以右拳反击对方的鼻子
Robinson comes back with a right on the nose,
拉莫塔打得他满场跑 头部一记左拳又一记右拳
La Motta drives him across the ring, a left and a right to the head.
一记左拳重击身体 罗宾森被击出场外
A hard left hand to the body, and Robinson is driven out of the ring
他在拳击生涯中首次被击倒
for the first knockdown of his career.
这是罗宾森最接近挫败的一次
This is the nearest Robinson has been to a loss.
比赛接近尾声,拉莫塔主导全局
The fight nears its end. La Motta has taken charge of the fight.
不败的罗宾森... 他的胜利快要不保了
The undefeated Sugar Ray... his winning ways are in jeopardy.
拉莫塔再度出击 拉莫塔假装出左拳
La Motta coming at him again, La Motta, feigning a left hand.
十局总分
After ten rounds,
罗西裁判八比二,拉莫塔胜
Judge Rossi, 8-2, La Motta.
莫菲裁判七比三,拉莫塔胜
Judge Murphy, 7-3, La Motta.
拉莫塔赢了比赛!
La Motta has won the fight!
大会一致决定布朗克斯公牛获胜
A unanimous decision for the Bronx Bull,
杰克拉莫塔让罗宾森体会到
Jake La Motta handing Sugar Ray Robinson
他职业生涯中的首次挫败 罗宾森非常不爽
his first loss as a professional and Robinson doesn't like it.
这次辉煌的胜利让拉莫塔
With this stunning victory, La Motta broke what was considered
打破了无敌罗宾森的纪录
the impossible... the invincible Sugar Ray's record.
拉莫塔证实了自己的实力
La Motta has proved himself a great fighter,
他应该有机会问鼎中量级冠军
and he shouldn't be denied a shot at the middleweight crown.
你确定我们要这么做?
You sure we should be doin' this?
过来
Come here.
你说绝不能在比赛前碰你
You said never to touch you before a fight.
过来,不然我打你一顿
Come here, before I give you a beatin'.
你说我不能的 你这两个星期都很乖
You said I couldn't. You've been good for two weeks.
过来
Come here.
摸我的庖庖
Touch my boo-boos.
小庖?
"Boo-ba?"
庖庖,亲庖庖一下
Boo-boo. Give the boo-boo a kiss.
让它好起来
Make it better.
脱了我的裤子
Take off my pants.
You know how to take off my pants?
把剩下的也脱了
Now take off the rest.
你要我保证不让你兴奋的
You made me promise not to get you excited.
没关系
Go ahead, do it.
把你的内裤脱掉
Take off your panties.
我喜欢体育馆的味道
I like the gym smell.
什么?
What?
我喜欢体育馆的味道
I like the smell of the gym.
不行,不行,够了,够了
No, no, no, no. Enough, enough.
不能再继续了 再继续,我就完了
I can't do any more. If I do any more, I'll sink it.
我得和罗宾森对打 我不能胡搞
I gotta fight Robinson, I can't fool around.
你做什么?
What are you doin'?
你做什么? 你在对我做什么?
What are you doin'? What are you doin' to me?
拉莫塔对决罗宾森 底特律,1943年
杰克拉莫塔和罗宾森
Jake La Motta and Sugar Ray Robinson
第三次对战
meet for the third time.
他们所向无敌,棋逢敌手
These men are unique, becoming classic rivals.
这两个凶狠无比的拳击手
These two men... fierce, powerful fighters,
危险至极... 令其他的拳击手望而却步
dangerous... so much so that no other fighter will go near them.
他们只好迎战对方 三个星期前后
And so, they fight each other, three weeks apart.
他们各胜一场
They've each won one,
照现在的情况看来 他们可能会再度对决
and they'll probably fight again, the way it looks now.
铃声响起,他们回到座位
They go to close quarters at the bell.
第七7局 罗宾森在得分上遥遥领先
Round 7, with Sugar Ray well ahead on points.
拉莫塔可能需要将他击倒
La Motta may need a knockout.
下巴一记左勾拳
The left hook to the jaw,
这是罗宾森 在拳击生涯中第二次被击倒
and Robinson is down for the second time in his career.
他在上一场也被击倒
He was down in the last fight, too.
拉莫塔看着裁判对罗宾森计时
La Motta watches Sugar Ray take the count from the referee.
-罗宾森试着爬起来 -...六...七...
- Robinson trying to get up. ...six... seven...
-八... -他站起来了
- eight... - He's up on his feet now,
裁判举起手套,他不能动了
and the referee is wiping off his gloves. He is stunned.
拉莫塔对他出击
La Motta comes at him.
罗宾森虽被击倒,仍在得分上领先
Despite being knocked down, Robinson is well ahead on points.
罗宾森以左勾拳击中下巴 一记左拳又一记右拳击中头部
He hooks a left to the jaw, a left and a right to the head by Robinson.
各位拳击迷请注意
Your attention, fans.
乔拉能汉裁判
Judge Joe Lanahan
计分八比一,一平
scores it 8-1, 1-even,
表决支持罗宾森!
in favor of Sugar Ray Robinson!
烂!烂!
Boo! Boo!
罗宾森获得裁判支持
A big vote for Sugar Ray Robinson.
...六比二,二平
...of 6-2, and 2-even,
大会一致决定胜利者是
for the winner by unanimous decision,
罗宾森!
Sugar Ray Robinson!
王八蛋!我他妈的...
Cocksuckers! I'd like to fuckin'...
-老天爷! -我要杀了那些王八蛋!
- For Christ's sake! - I'll kill those cocksuckers!
他们会判他获胜
They only gave him that fuckin' decision
是因为他下星期要从军 那是唯一的理由
'cause he's goin' in the Army next week, that's the only reason.
我把他击倒了 我不知道还要怎么样
I knocked him down, I don't know what else I gotta do.
-我到底要怎么样? -你赢了,他们耍你!
- What the hell I gotta do? - You won and they robbed ya!
他们真可悲 因为他们的老妈是婊子
They're miserable, because their mothers take it up
难怪他们这样!
the fuckin' ass, that's why!
我干了不少坏事,乔伊 也许是我的报应
I've done a lot of bad things, Joey. Maybe it's comin' back to me.
谁知道?也许我是衰鬼 谁知道呢?
Who knows? I'm a jinx, maybe. Who the hell knows?
别管那些狗屁...是你赢了
Forget about all that shit... this was your shot.
他们耍了我们! 一次又一次耍了我们!
They robbed us! They out and out robbed us!
-维琪来了,你要和她说话吗? -我不想和任何人说话
- It's Vickie, you wanna talk to her? - I don't wanna talk to nobody.
-乔伊,送她回家 -好
- Joey, take her home. - All right.
-你没有问题吧? -对,没问题
- You gonna be all right? - Yeah, I'll be all right.
你确定?
You sure?
-看着她啊 -好的
- Make sure she's all right. - All right.
拉莫塔对季维
底特律 1944年1月14日
拉莫塔对巴索拉
纽约市 1945年8月10日
拉莫塔对柯强 纽约市1945年9月17日
拉莫塔对艾德加 底特律1946年6月12日
拉莫塔对赛特菲尔 芝加哥1946年9月12日
妈咪的小帮手
拉莫塔对贝尔 纽约市1947年3月14日
佩尔汉大道
纽约市布朗克斯区 1947年
对,孩子 我会回来再教训你一次
Yeah, child, I am coming back and bash you on your head one more time.
不准再有吉尼洛事件
Don't ever do that Janiro bullshit again,
别再安排那种比赛,听到了没?
no more deals like that, you hear what I'm sayin'?
-你在说什么? -我在说什么?
- What are you talkin' about? - What am I talkin' about?
你看...一百六十八磅呀
Look at that... 168 pounds.
-别再吃了 -这算什么回答?
- Stop eatin'. - What's with the smart answers?
我是不是一开始就说过我不想打?
I told ya I didn't wanna do it in the first place, didn't I?
没有,你没说
No, you didn't say that.
你明明说你可以减到一百五十五磅
You're the one that told me you could get down to 155 pounds.
我从哪听来的? 难道是我自己编的吗?
Where'd I get it? Did I pull it out of the fuckin' air?
我不知道能不能减到一百五十五磅
I don't know if I'm gonna make it down to 155.
能减到一百六十磅就算走运了
I'm lucky I make it to 160.
还有,你帮我登记的 参赛体重是一百五十五磅
And on top of that, you sign me for a fight at 155,
如果减不到一百五十五 我就丧失一万五千美元?!
and If I don't make the 155, I lose $15,000?!
-没错 -你是我的经纪人耶!
- That's right. - You're supposed to be a manager!
你要知道你在干嘛才对
You're supposed to know what you're doin'.
-我做我想做的事 -那正是我担心的...
- I did just what I wanted to do. - That's what I'm worried about, you...
-你想打进冠军赛吗? -你在说什么?
- You want a title shot? - What are ya talkin' about?
-你要打冠军赛吗? -这是马戏团吗?
- Do you want a title shot? - What am I, in a circus over here?
他都比你有常识,你在做什么?
I ask him, he's got more sense about this. What are you doin'?
你已经奋斗三年了,对不对?
You been killin' yourself for three years now, right?
已经没有人能和你比赛了 大家都害怕和你比赛
There's nobody's left for you to fight. Everybody's afraid to fight you.
这小子吉尼洛出现 他搞不清楚状况
Along comes this kid Janiro. He don't know any better.
他是刚出道的小伙子 愿意和任何人比赛
He's a young kid, up and comin', he'll fight anybody.
很好,你和他打
Good, you fight him.
痛扁他一顿,让他惨败 你担心什么?
Bust his hole. Tear him apart. What are you worried about?
你有什么好担心的?
What's the biggest thing you got to worry about?
-我担心我的体重 -你担心体重?
- I'm worried about the weight. - You're worried about the weight?
我们在吵什么? 我说了是体重
What we arguin' for? I just said the weight.
就算你因为体重的关系输了
Let's say you lose because of your weight.
他们会认为 你不像从前一样强了吗?
Are they gonna think you're not as tough as you were?
你不是同一个拳击手了吗?
You're not the same fighter?
那也好,他们会帮你安排
Good. They'll match you with all those guys
那些过去不敢和你比赛的人
they were afraid to match you with you before.
结果呢?你会痛宰他们 他们就得让你进入冠军赛
What happens? You'll kill 'em. And they gotta give you a title shot.
-拜托给我咖啡 -为什么?因为没别人了
- Bring me coffee, please. - Why? There's nobody else.
已经没人了
Nobody's left.
-他们还能让谁参赛? -咖啡
- Who they gonna give it to? - Coffee.
-马上来 -你听到没?
- In a minute. - You listenin' to me?
-拜托,甜心,给我咖啡 -好,等一下
- Please, honey, bring me the coffee. - All right, just a minute.
-我要等多久? -你有没有在听?
- How long I gotta wait?! - Are you listenin'?
假设你赢了,你打败吉尼洛
Now let's say you win, you beat Janiro.
你本来就该打败他,对不对?
Which you definitely should beat him, right?
-对 -对不对?
- Yeah. - Right?
-对 -他们还是会让你
- Yeah. - They still gotta give you
进入冠军赛,知道为什么吗?
a shot at the title. You know why?
-为什么? -因为我说过了
- Why? - 'Cause the same thing as before,
已经没人了,没别人可以赢
there's nobody left, there ain't nobody around.
他们非让你赢不可
They gotta give you the shot.
你明白吗? 如果你赢,你是赢家
Ya understand? If you win, you win.
如果你输,你还是赢家
If you lose, you still win.
你不可能输的 而且你完全靠自己
There's no way you can lose, and you do it on your own,
正如你所愿,不靠任何人帮忙
just the way you wanted to do it, without help from anybody.
你明白吗? 减到一百五十五磅就对了,大胖子
Ya understand? Just get down to 155 pounds, ya fat bastard.
别再吃就没问题了 不吃而已,你做得到的
Stop eatin'. What's the problem? Stop eatin', that's all, you can do it.
你什么都不懂,你明白吗?
You don't understand anything, do you understand that?
乔伊说得对 这个吉尼洛是刚出道的拳击手
Joey's right, this Janiro is an up-and-coming fighter,
他长得帅又受欢迎
he's good-lookin', he's popular.
-你把他打败... -抱歉,你什么意思
- You beat him now... - Excuse me, what do you mean,
-长得帅? -我没说“长得帅”
- good-lookin'? - I'm not sayin' good-lookin',
-我是说受欢迎,如果你赢了... -你刚才说什么...
- I'm sayin' popular. If you win... - But what were you just sayin'
-长得帅又受欢迎? -我没什么意思
- about good-lookin', popular? - I'm not sayin' anything.
-我只是说乔伊说得对 -你是权威吗?
- I'm just tellin' you Joey's right. - Are you an authority, or what?
-没有... -出去
- Nothin'... - Get outta here.
出去,把宝宝带出去
Get outta here. Take the baby and get outta here.
每个人突然都变成权威了
Everybody all of a sudden's an authority about this.
第一,她怎么知道他长得帅?
Where'd she find out he's good-lookin', first of all?
她没有什么意思
She didn't mean nothin'.
谁问你了?
Who asked you?
现在你要和我吵吗?
You gonna start with me now?
别人在讲话就不能插嘴
When people are talkin', you don't interrupt.
这不关你的事 尤其是我哥和他老婆之间的事
It's none of your business, especially if it's my brother and his wife.
和你一点关系也没有
Ain't got nothin' to do with you.
走开,进去,带宝宝进去
Get outta here, go inside. Take the baby inside.
来,咱们离开这些凶巴巴的人
Come on. Let's leave the grouches here, okay?
-走吧 -看不出来该换尿布了吗?
- Come on. - Change her diapers, can't you see?
-她又要哭了,她好臭 -是你害她哭的
- She's gonna cry, she stinks. - You make her cry.
-待会我让你哭 -来,走吧
- I'm gonna make you cry. - Yeah. Mm-hmm. Come on.
-他们不懂事 -一百五十五磅...
- They're a couple of babies. - 155 pounds...
咱们去训练营
let's go to the training camp.
不受干扰,没有老婆,电话
No distractions, no wives, no phone calls.
没有人会烦你 我来拟出你的行程表
Nobody around to bother you. I'll write out your usual schedule,
-你的饮食... -听着,我想问你一件事
- your usual diet... - Listen, I wanna ask you somethin'.
我不在的时候 你有没有注意到她怪怪的?
When I'm away, you ever notice anything funny goin' on with her?
-谁,维琪吗? -对
- With who, Vickie? - Yeah.
比如说?
Like what?
你认为我是什么意思?
What do you think I mean?
我没注意到任何事
No, I don't notice anything.
我要你盯着她,好吗?
I want you to keep an eye on her, all right?
为什么,杰克? 她又没做错事
For what, Jack? She don't do anything wrong.
我不在的时候 我要你盯着她,好吗?
I want you to keep an eye on her when I'm away, all right?
你无缘无故找麻烦 我告诉你,你快不行了
You just start trouble for nothin', I'm tellin' ya, you're crackin' up.
我有理由的,好吗?
I got a reason, right?
你我都知道 女人只要找对时间
You and I both know, any woman, given the right time,
只要天时地利人和 她们就会乱来
the right place, the right circumstances, they'll do anything, right?
什么事都可能发生,好吗?
I mean, anything's possible. All right?
-你说得对 -你知道的
- You're right. - You oughta know.
你没说错,可是 你在找她麻烦,我刚才有看到
You're not wrong, but you're pickin' on this girl, 'cause I saw you before.
你在担心你的体重 然后愈说愈烦闷
You're worried about your weight, you're gettin' aggravated,
你跟她说“什么?进去,谁问你了?”
and you tell her, "What are you? Go inside. Who asked ya?"
你拿那种事烦她 等于让她有借口出去
Botherin' her for that, you're gonna give her an excuse to go out.
-她在讲一个男人 -又怎样?
- She was talkin' about a guy. - So?
又怎样? 她在替你说话,她又没有...
So what? She was talkin' on your behalf, she wasn't...
替我说话?她在讲 一个小帅哥,说他长得帅
On my behalf? She was talkin' about a pretty kid, sayin' he's good-lookin'.
你在说什么?
What are you talkin' about?
那你就让他难看啊,那又怎样?
So you make him ugly, what's the difference?
-为什么? -你别管,照做就是了
- That's why? - Never mind, just do it.
好啦
All right.
你知道你该怎么做? 进去,对她好一点
You know what you should do? Go inside and be nice to her.
跟她和好
Make up with her.
跟她说你要带她出门 我们都出门
Tell her you're gonna take her out, we'll go out.
你想在离开前出去玩玩吧?
You wanna go out before you go away, don't you?
这样你才能放心地离开
This way, you go away with a clear head.
你带她出去
You know you took her out,
享用美酒大餐,开心一下
you wined and dined her, you had a good time.
好吗?
All right?
好,你想去哪?
All right. Where do you wanna go?
-“出去”就对了 -好
- Well, "out" out, you know. - All right.
听着,把她拉到旁边去说
Listen, though, if you tell her now, pull her on the side.
别在莉诺面前说...
Don't say nothin' in front of Lenore...
-我不要带她去 -你想太多了
- 'cause I'm not takin' her. - It's on your head.
-好 -她不必跟我们去
- All right. - We can go without her.
-你想干嘛就干嘛 -我是啊
- Do what you're gonna do. - Oh, I am.
过来
Come here.
各位女士先生晚安
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen,
很高兴回到柯帕酒馆来
it's great to be back in the Copa Lounge.
真优秀的观众
What a great audience.
小姐,笑一个嘛 你进来的时候我就有笑你
Come on, lady, laugh it up... I laughed when you come in.
不过说真的,各位 今晚我们有一位贵宾
But seriously speakin', folks, we have a special guest with us tonight.
向大家介绍中量级的拳击好手
I'd like to introduce the world's leading middleweight contender,
布朗克斯公牛,发威的公牛
the Bronx Bull, the raging bull.
欢迎了不起的杰克拉莫塔 各位女士先生
Let's hear it for the great Jake La Motta, ladies and gentlemen.
你说你叫什么名字?
What's your name again?
-珍娜 -珍娜,抱歉,只是...
- Janet. - Janet, sorry, yeah, just been...
敬酒的时候到了
It's, uh, toast time.
他用左勾拳打我 没有拳,他只有一个钩子
He hits me with a left hook... no hand, just a hook he had.
-你要去哪里? -去厕所
- Where you goin'? - Goin' to the bathroom.
嘿,维琪
Hey, Vickie.
-嗨 -老天,你真美
- Hi. - Gee, you're lookin' great.
-谢谢 -乔伊有来吗?
- Thanks. - Joe here?
对,他们在那里,杰克也在
Yeah, they're over there. Jake's here, too.
太好了,听着
That's great. Listen, I'm over here
我和汤米和几个兄弟坐那里
with Tommy and some of the old gang.
你有空就过来喝一杯
You get a chance, come over and have a drink.
待会见
See ya later.
-杰克,你好吗? -你好吗?
- Hello, Jake, how are you? - How you doin'?
你没喝酒吧?
You're not drinkin', are ya?
-乔伊,你好吗? -你好吗,沙维?
- Joey, how are ya? - How you doin', Sal?
你们还真热闹
Look like you're havin' a ball over here.
我和汤米康伯坐在那边
I'm over there with Tommy Como.
你们何不过来喝一杯?
Why don't you come over and have a drink?
汤米来了?我没看到他进来
Tommy's here? I didn't even see him come in.
查理,我们在这里做什么?
Charlie Rocks, what are we gonna do here?
什么消息?胜算多少?
What you got? What's the odds?
待会见,乔伊
I'll see you later, Joey.
西装真不赖 他看来不错吧,杰克?
Hey, that's some suit. He looks good, huh, Jack?
我以为那是我最棒的笑话
I thought that was my best joke.
丽塔,看谁来了
Rita, Look who's here.
嗨,维琪
Hi, Vickie.
嘿,维琪
Hey, Vickie.
-跟汤米打招呼 -你好吗,甜心?
- Say hello to Tommy. - How are ya, honey?
很高兴看到你,和查理打招呼
Good to see ya. Say hello to Charlie.
-坐下来喝一杯 -不了,我得回去找杰克
- Sit down, have a drink. - I can't, I have to get back to Jake.
-我只是过来打个招呼 -好,甜心,谢谢你过来
- I just came by to say hello. - All right, honey, thanks for comin' by.
-维琪这孩子不错 -她和那个无赖在一起
- Not a bad kid, that Vickie, ya know. - She's with that fuckin' gorilla.
她一定被那家伙打得很惨
She must've caught a hundred beatin's off that guy.
-你怎么去那么久? -我去汤米那桌打声招呼
- What took ya so long? - I went by Tommy's table to say hello.
我看到你和他们打招呼 但怎么去那么久?
I saw you say hello to them all. But what took ya so long?
没有,我打个招呼就回来了
Nothin', I said hello. I came back.
-你还说了什么? -他问我要不要喝一杯
- What else did you say? - He asked me if I wanted a drink.
我说“不了,杰克和乔伊在那边” 然后我就离开了
I said, "No, Jake and Joey are over there," and I left.
你干嘛和沙维说话?
What were you talkin' to Salvy for?
他问我乔伊有没有来 我说“他在那里”
He asked me if Joey was there, I said, "He's over there."
然后他说“汤米在那里 你要不要去打个招呼?”我就去了
Then he said, "Tommy's over there, why don't you go say hello?" And I did.
你对他有意思吗?
Are you interested in him?
没有,我怎么会对他有意思?
No, why would I be interested in him?
你确定你对他没有意思?
You sure you're not interested in him?
对
Yeah.
换句话说,你对他没意思 但是你有可能对别人
In other words, you're not interested in him, but you could be interested
-有意思吧? -杰克,别再说了
- in somebody? - Jake, don't start.
你干嘛...?闭嘴,不然我就扁你
What do you gotta? Hey, shut up, or I'm gonna smack you in the face.
你让我丢脸
You embarrass me.
这是康伯先生请的
These are from Mr. Como.
我可以拿走...?
Shall I take the?
-什么? -我可以拿走吗?
- What? - Should I take this?
-你喝完了吗? -我还没喝完
- Are you finished? - I'm not through with it.
-好 -笑话讲完了,各位
- Okay. - These are the jokes, folks.
老实说,真是... 你好吗,你这个秃头同性恋?
I tell ya the truth, it's so... Hi, how are ya, you bald-headed fag?
-嘿,乔伊 -汤米,谢谢你的酒
- Hey, Joey. - Tommy, thanks for the drinks.
-别客气了 -查理,你好吗?
- Come on, any time. - Charlie, how are ya?
你好吗,乔伊?一切都好吗?
How you doin', Joey? How's everything?
-杰克呢? -他在那里,他不想过来
- Where's Jake? - He's over there, he don't wanna come.
-如果你叫他,他就会来 -好吧
- If you call him, he'll come. - All right.
-我马上回来 -他来了
- I'll be right back. - Here he comes.
怎么回事?你都不打电话了
What is it? You don't call anybody anymore.
我们都见不到你了,真是的
We never see ya anymore. For cryin' out loud.
你都不出现了? 连个电话也不打?怎么回事?
You never come around anymore? You can't even make a call? What is it?
我忙嘛 我到处去打拳,我很忙
I'm busy, I'm goin' away fightin', I'm busy.
真忙 你看他还以为我是认真的
Busy, busy. Look at him takin' me seriously.
我只是开玩笑,这小子真是的
I'm only kiddin' you, what a fuckin' kid.
-这位是最强的拳击手 -嘿,杰克
- That's the best fuckin' fighter around. - Hey, Jake.
-你好吗? -那些外劳
- How you doin'? - Them mulignanes,
想都别想,他们都怕跟你对打
forget about it, they're all afraid to fight you.
-你还好吗? -我很好
- How you feelin', all right? - I'm all right.
-很好?很强? -很强,我没问题
- Good? Strong? - Strong, yeah. I'm doin' okay.
那么吉尼洛得小心了,对吧?
Then Janiro's gotta watch his ass, right?
他是该小心
I think he should.
前三,四场比赛 这家伙让我赢不少钱
Last three, four times, I won nothin' but money with the guy.
他可不简单,优秀的拳击手
He's no piece of cake, that's a good fighter.
这家伙很帅,女人都喜欢他
Very attractive guy. All the girls like him.
没有疤痕,小白脸
No marks, clean.
杰克,是真的吗? 你的体重增加了?
Jake, am I wrong? Did you gain a few pounds?
只增加几磅 一下就可以减掉,没问题
A few pounds. I'll knock it off right away, though, no problem.
一下就减掉
Right off, right off.
我问你哦,我只是随便聊聊
Look, let me ask you somethin'. I'm just talkin' now, just talkin'.
如果我跟你说 你跟吉尼洛的这场比赛
I come to you, and I'm tellin' you that I'm gonna bet a lot of money on you
我会押很多钱在你身上
in this fight with Janiro, right?
怎样?
Yeah?
你会说什么? 你会对我说什么?
What would you tell me? What could you say to me?
我会说把全部的家当都押下去
I would say bet everything you got.
-全部? -全部
- Everything? - Everything.
因为我要打得他屁滚尿流
'Cause I'm gonna open his hole like this.
原谅我说粗话,小姐们
Excuse my French, girls.
-我要让他痛不欲生 -这家伙怎么了?
- I'm gonna make him suffer. - What's wrong with this guy?
我要让他妈后悔生了他
I'm gonna make his mother wish she never had him.
-这是私人恩怨吗? -把他打成肉饼,什么?
- Is this somethin' personal? - Make him into dog meat. What?
-他对报社说了什么吗? -没有,他是个好孩子
- Did he say somethin' in the papers? - No, he's a nice kid.
他还长得很清秀
He's a pretty kid, too.
我很困扰,我不知道... 该上他还是打他
I don't know, I got a problem... if I should fuck him or fight him.
你一定疯了...上他还是打他
Must be crazy. Fuck him or fight him.
你很有可能被这小子干掉,小心
You're really liable to get fucked with this kid, watch out.
-被谁? -吉尼洛
- By who? - Janiro.
你是说你要我找他上你?
You mean you want me to get him to fuck you?
-我? -对
- Me? - Yeah.
-不,我不要他上我 -我可以轻易办到
- No, I don't want him to fuck me. - I could do that easily.
你要怎么做?
How you gonna do that?
把你们两个弄上场 再把你们痛扁一顿
I'll get youse both in the ring and give youse both a fuckin' beatin',
然后你们就可以上对方
and you both could fuck each other.
-我会血流成河 -你习惯了
- I'll get all full of blood. - You're used to that.
好了,喝吧 那是姜汁汽水,杰克
Come on, drink up. That's ginger ale, Jake.
-来,干杯 -干杯
- Come on, salute. - Salute.
-杰克,祝你好运 -干杯,祝你好运,杰克
- Jake, good luck. - Salute. Good luck, Jake.
嘿,维琪
Hey, Vick.
-干嘛? -你醒着吗?
- What? - You awake?
没有
No.
-你听得到吗? -干嘛?
- Can you hear me? - What?
我们在床上的时候...
You ever think of anybody else...
你会想着别人吗?
when we're in bed?
-什么意思? -就是我们做爱的时候
- What do you mean? - You know, when we make love.
没有别人,我爱你
No, nobody, I love you.
你为什么那样说吉尼洛?
How come you said that thing about Janiro?
-我说什么? -你说他长得帅
- What did I say? - You said he had a pretty face.
我没注意过他的脸
I never noticed his face.
那你为什么那么说?
How come you said that, then?
我根本不知道我说了什么 我连他长什么样子都不知道
I don't even know what I said. I don't even know what he looks like.
睡觉吧
Go to sleep.
拉莫塔对吉尼洛 纽约市1947年
-他帅不起来了 -他把他打得好惨
- He ain't pretty no more. - He really messed him up.
大会一致决定这十局比赛
And the winner by unanimous decision
胜利者是杰克拉莫塔!
in ten rounds, Jake La Motta!
给我一点冰块 一小片润润舌头就好
Give me a little piece of ice, just a sliver, just for my tongue.
-不能喝水! -别这样,我快死了
- No water! - Come on, I'm dyin'.
老顽固
Fuckin' hard-on.
四磅
Four pounds.
继续练,废话少说
Keep workin'. Cut the bullshit.
我看到他和吉尼洛的比赛 我不敢相信...
I saw him fight with Janiro, I couldn't believe it...
他把他毁了,精彩得不得了
destroyed this guy, it was absolutely incredible.
他把他的鼻子整个打歪了
He knocked his nose from one side of his face to the other.
-你开玩笑 -都快掉下来了
- You've gotta be kiddin'. - Fuckin' thing was hangin' off.
你们接下来跟谁打? 你能告诉我吗?
Who you fightin' next? Can you tell me?
我不知道,这无法预料的...
I don't know. You never know these things...
在我看来 他们非让他打冠军赛不可
From all I've seen, they gotta give him that title shot.
杰克柯提,乔伊
Jackie Curtie, Joey.
-你们应该认识 -嗨,乔伊
- You should know each other. - Hi, Joey.
幸会...久仰大名
Pleasure... heard a lot of nice things about you.
我们会进入冠军赛的
We're gonna get the title shot, too.
我相信,我欣赏你哥哥 我靠他赚了不少钱
I'm sure. I like your brother. Made a lot of money on him.
我相信我的麻烦比他多
Probably more than he did, that's for sure.
他和奥斯卡杰克森那场比赛 让我大赚一笔
Made some nice cabbage on the Oscar Jackson fight.
奥斯卡后来去哪了?
What ever happened to Oscar?
-有人再见过他吗? -他被打得很惨,搞不好死了
- Anybody see him anymore? - He's punchy, he probably died.
谁在乎啊?
Who the fuck cares?
-你们别客气 -桌子很漂亮
- Make yourselves comfortable. - It's a beautiful table.
-这里最糟的桌子 -他在抱怨了
- The worst table in the house. - And he's complainin'.
很漂亮的桌子
It's a beautiful table.
他在市中心工作 在大楼里...管理电梯
He's workin' downtown, big building... workin' an elevator.
我那天刚好经过
Happened to be there the other day.
我不是意大利人,我不在乎
I'm not Italian, I don't care.
-他送我上楼 -嘿,那个奥斯卡
- Took me right up. - Hey, that Oscar's always
是个正直的人 乔伊,他帮了你不少
a stand-up guy, Joey, he did you a lot of good.
也让你哥打了一场苦战
Gave your brother a hell of a fight, too.
米奇? 我要威士忌加水
Yeah, Mickey? Cutty Sark and water.
失陪一下,两位
Excuse me one minute, fellas.
-我马上回来 -要回来,乔伊
- I'll be right back. - Come back, Joey.
马上回来
Come on back. Okay.
-嘿 -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿,乔
Hey, Joe.
-嘿,乔伊 -你看他看我们的样子
- Hey, Joey. - Look at how he's lookin' at us.
-出事了 -她会有麻烦
- Something's happening. - She's having a problem.
-你担心吗? -我只是坐在那儿喝一杯!
- You're worried about it? - I'm just sittin' there havin' a drink!
-闭嘴,别多话 -你们两个都一样
- Shut up. Keep your mouth shut. - Both of youse are the same.
我觉得像个囚犯
I feel like I'm a prisoner.
走个路或多看别人一眼就被骂
I can't walk, I look at somebody the wrong way, I get smacked.
你以为你没做错吗,还这么大声?
You think you're right or somethin', the way you're fuckin' yellin'?
-我没错 -你错了
- I am right. - You're wrong.
我没错,我受够你们两个
I am right. I'm tired of having to turn around
老是找我的麻烦
and havin' both of youse up my ass all the time.
-闭嘴 -不要
- Shut up. - No.
-别逼我... -我受够了听你废话
- Don't make me... - I'm tired of listenin' to you
-还有你哥哥,我没错 -别逼我在这里发飙
- and your brother. I'm not wrong. - Don't make me get nuts in this place.
你要我怎么办?
What am I supposed to do?
我二十岁了 却得每晚回家自己一个人睡觉?
I'm 20 years old, I gotta go home and sleep by myself every night?
-你干嘛嫁给他? -因为我爱他
- What the fuck did you marry him for? - 'Cause I love him.
-是吗? -对,我爱他
- You do? - Yeah, I love him.
但你要我怎么办? 他根本不想上我
What am I supposed to do? This guy don't even wanna fuck me.
他只是参赛太久了
He's just been a contender too long.
等他赢得冠军就好了 到时候就没事了
He'll be all right as soon as he gets his shot, and then everything'll be okay.
你就不必像个花痴一样乱跑了
You won't have to go fuckin' runnin' around when he does.
杰克不可能成为冠军 太多人讨厌他了
Jake is never gonna be champ. Too many people hate him.
-而你却和那些人喝酒! -我要把我的酒喝完
- And you're drinking with them! - And I'm gonna finish my drink
-而且我要开心一下 -去拿你的东西
- and I'm gonna have a good time. - Get your stuff.
我说了你不能留在这里
I said you ain't stayin' here.
-去拿你的东西 -我要留下来
- Get your stuff. - I'm stayin'.
你在让我哥哥出糗,去拿东西
You're making an asshole out of my brother, get your stuff.
-别激动嘛 -闭嘴
- Come on, relax. - Shut up.
管你自己它妈的的事,闭嘴
Mind your fuckin' business and shut up.
-你误会我们了 -我是不是叫你闭嘴?
- You're taking this all wrong. - I said shut up, didn't I?!
你怎么回事? 我们又没有做什么
What's the matter with you? There's nothin' goin' on here.
我们是清白的 我们只是喝几杯酒
This is innocent. We're only having a few drinks.
-别激动,没问题 -你知道不是那么一回事
- Relax, no problem. - Come on, you know better than that.
-好了,大家都冷静下来 -别激动嘛
- All right. Let's all calm down. - Just relax, come on.
-我们是多年的朋友了 -我只是不爽
- We've been friends a long time. - I'm just upset.
-她是我大嫂... -我们没有做什么
- It's my brother's wife... - There's nothing goin' on over here.
对不起,真的
I'm sorry, I really am.
大家是朋友,可以讲清楚的...
We're friends, we can straighten this...
是吗?没做什么?!
Right? Nothing going on?!
没做什么?!你这个下三滥!
Nothing going on?! Ya dirty cocksucker!
-你这老不死的! -放开!叫他放手!
- Fuckin' hard-on! - Get off! Get him off!
我要狠狠教训你一顿,下三滥!
I'll bite your fuckin' head off, ya cocksucker!
滚出去,乔伊! 你在搞什么啊?!
Get outta here, Joey! What the fuck are you doin'?!
-小心点!别这样! -别碰我!
- Easy, easy! Come on! - Get your hands off me!
-别这样! -别这样!
- Come on! - Come on!
混蛋
Fuckin' cunt.
滚!滚出去!
Get out! Get outta the way!
杂碎!我要把你的眼睛挖出来!
Oh, scumbag! I'm gonna suck your fuckin' eyes out!
你混帐...你疯了吗?
Hey, you fuckin'... what are you, nuts?!
别提到汤米
Don't mention Tommy.
咱们最好井水不犯河水
You do what you do, and we do what we gotta do.
-别扯到别人 -你误会了,乔
- Don't mention no names. - No, you're wrong, Joe.
他误会了 别在这里惹麻烦
He's wrong. No fuckin' trouble in the joint.
我叫你滚出去,你这个无赖!
I said get outta here, ya fuckin' mamone!
给我过来,你混蛋!
Get back there, ya fuck, ya!
大家别激动,别激动嘛
Take it easy, people. Come on, now, take it easy.
你完了,你这个王八蛋!
You've had it, you rat bastard!
迪邦奈俱乐部
会员专属
你们两个认识很多年了
You guys have a lot of years between you,
你们一起做了不少事
and you've done a lot of things together.
我明白她是你的大嫂,乔伊
I understand, Joey, it was your brother's wife.
但是你不能打人
But you don't raise your hands,
你不能在那样的地方闹事
you don't create a scene like that in a place like that.
现在大家都把话说清楚了
Now, we've heard everybody's point of view here,
我们要把这件事给忘了
and we're gonna forget about it.
这种事不该忘 但是我们要把它忘掉
I shouldn't forget about it, but we're gonna forget about it.
好吗?
Right?
现在我要你们两个
What I want you to do now, you two guys,
握手和好,把这整件事忘了
I want you to shake hands, forget this whole thing,
不要记恨
and no grudges.
那是最重要的...不要记恨
That's the most important thing... no grudges.
好,来握个手吧
Now, come on, shake hands.
只要你没问题,我就没问题
It's all right with me if it's all right with you.
好吗?
All right?
真希望没发生这种事
I only wish this thing never happened.
我们都希望没这回事
We all wish it never happened.
好吗?你不会有事的
Right? You'll get over it.
沙维,让我和他单独谈谈
Salvy, let me talk with him alone a minute.
好啊
Yeah, all right.
咱们星期一,二或改天见?
I'll see you Monday, Tuesday or somethin', all right?
对不起,我忘了
I'm sorry, I forgot all about it.
你疯了吗?痛死我了
What are you, fucking nuts? You're killin' me.
先不管这些,家里都好吧?
Aside from everything else, is the family all right?
对,他们都好,大家都好
Yeah, they're fine. Everybody's fine.
你怎么搞的?不会说话吗?
What is it with you? You can't talk?
-我说了啊,什么意思? -我知道
- I'm talkin', what do you mean? - I know.
你这是什么态度? 我真搞不懂你
Why have you got this funny attitude? I can't figure you out.
这么简短的回答? “对,他们都好”
What is it with all the quick answers? "Yeah, they're all right. Yeah."
你想赶快离开这儿是不是?
You wanna get outta here fast or something?
不,没这回事
No, it's nothin' like that.
只是因为之前的气,还有...
It's just all the aggravation and everything and...
打了一场架嘛
all the fights and all.
听我说,杰克他...
Listen to me. Now, Jake...
这家伙很让人难堪
the guy's become an embarrassment.
他让我在一些人的面前难堪
He's embarrassin' me with certain people,
我的面子挂不住
and I'm lookin' very bad.
我想提拔他这个自己人都不行
I can't deliver a kid from my own goddamn neighborhood.
他有什么问题?
What is it with him?
他干嘛跟自己过不去?
Why does he have to make it so hard on himself?
他来找我,我就让他平步青云
He comes to me, I make it easier for him.
他真是死脑筋
The man's got a head of rock.
这很难解释,汤米,他...
You know, it's hard to explain, Tommy, he's...
杰克尊敬你
Jack respects you.
他根本不跟人打招呼的
I mean, he don't even say hello to anybody.
但是他跟你说话,他喜欢你
You he talks to, he likes you.
只是当他拿定主意的时候
It's just that when he gets somethin' on his mind,
他就很固执,他喜欢我行我素
he's got a hard head, he likes to do things his own way.
耶稣可以走下十字架来
Jesus Christ could come off the cross sometimes,
他也不在乎,他只要随心所欲
he don't give a fuck, he's gonna do what he wants to do,
他想靠自己成功 他认为他可以靠自己成功
he wants to make it on his own. He thinks he can make it on his own.
靠自己成功
Make it on his own.
他以为他可以靠自己就变成冠军?
He thinks he's gonna walk in there and become champion on his own?
-他疯了,你知道他疯了 -对,他疯了
- He's crazy. You know he's nuts. - Yeah, he's crazy.
是他不尊重任何人 他谁的话也不听
And he's got no respect for nobody, he doesn't listen to nobody.
不是因为他疯了
That's not crazy.
-不过他尊重你 -他谁也不尊重
- He respects you, though. - He doesn't respect anybody.
你帮我这个忙,懂不懂?
Now, you do this for me, you understand?
你去跟他说 我才不在乎他有多厉害
You tell him I don't care how colorful he is, how great he is.
他可以打败世上所有的
He could beat all the Sugar Ray Robinsons
罗宾森和吉尼洛
and the Tony Janiros in the world.
但是他进不了冠军赛的 没有我们帮忙就不可能
But he ain't gonna get a shot at that title, not without us, he ain't.
你是个聪明人
Now, you're a smart kid.
你去找他,跟他说...
You go to him, you tell him...
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
这双鞋花了二十大元
Twenty dollar shoe here.
你不问我出了什么事吗?
Aren't you gonna ask me what happened?
怎么了?
What's the matter?
-怎么回事? -我记得在这里见到她的
- What's wrong? - I remember when I met her here.
-谁? -维琪
- Who? - Vickie.
怎么了?她又做了什么?
Why, what's the matter? What'd she do now?
我知道她在搞鬼 我真想逮到她一次
I know she's doin' somethin', I just wanna catch her once.
一次就好
Just once.
杰克,帮你自己一个忙好不好?
Hey, Jack. Wanna do yourself a favor?
把她扁一顿,赶出去
Bust her fuckin' hole, throw her out.
不然就和她在一起 让她毁了你的一生
Either that, or live with her and let her ruin your life,
因为她毁了你的生活
'cause that's what's happenin'.
你还能忍多久? 你还要吃几次瘪?
How much could you take? How much shit could you take?
他说了什么?
So, what'd that guy say?
他还是照旧给我“好消息加坏消息”
He gave me the old "good news, bad news" routine.
好消息是
The good news is
你可以进入冠军赛
you're gonna get the shot at the title.
坏消息是他们要你听他们的
The bad news is they want you to do the old flip-flop for them.
-能讲点新鲜的吗? -你说呢?
- So, what else is new? - What'd you expect?
你没猜到这些吗?
You didn't know that was comin'?
有赢就有输吧
You win some, you lose some.
这一次我们输了
This one, we're losin'.
比利法克斯
Billy Fox.
一百七十三又四份三磅
173 and 3/4 pounds.
-杰克拉莫塔,一百六十七... -你应该已经听说了
- Jake La Motta. 167... - I guess you've heard by now
到处都有传闻,有不少谣言
a lot of the stuff that's goin' around, a lot of rumors.
说真的,不久前大家都捧你
Matter of fact, a short time ago you were a big favorite,
突然间,你成了不抢手的丧家之犬
and all of a sudden, you're a 12-5 underdog,
大家都在讲,就这么简单
and people are talkin', it's as simple as that.
-真有趣,我从没听过 -可是外面都在传
- That's funny, I never heard anything. - It's out there, though,
而且很难听
and It's not good.
老实说,这场比赛的赌注取消了
As a matter of fact, the bets are off on this one.
这场没人要赌
Nothin' goin' in this one.
而且椿脚都在说你快不行了
Matter of fact, smart money is sayin' that you're getting ready to hit the tank.
-真是胡说 -对啊,胡说
- That's bullshit. - Yeah, that's bullshit.
你有钱想下注吗?
You got any money you wanna bet?
-别这样 -我行的,尽管下
- Come on. - I'll take the action, go ahead.
你就押法克斯吧 因为我最后会赢
You bet it on Fox, 'cause I'm gonna win.
我不可能倒下 谁都不会让我倒下
There's no way I'm goin' down. I don't go down for nobody.
-我只想听你说 -你要知道
- That's what I wanted to hear. - I want you to know that.
-好 -好的,上校
- All right. - All right, Colonel.
好,没事
Okay, that's it.
你跑下来就说这个?
You came down here just for that nonsense?
-就这样? -就这样
- That was it? - That was it.
拉莫塔对法克斯 纽约1947年
各位女士先生晚安
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到麦迪森广场花园
Welcome to the Madison Square Garden
最热门的地方
feature attraction.
-这边是一百七十五磅的... -长官,拍张照吧?
- In this corner, weighing 175 pounds... - Commissioner, how about a picture?
各位,这里可以拍张照吗?
Fellas, can we get a picture over here?
不败的比利法克斯
...the undefeated Billy Fox.
史帝夫,你弟弟出院了吗?
Hi, Steve. Your brother got out of the hospital?
-他们认为没有大碍 -他出院了?很好
- They think it's all right. - Did he get out? Good.
-查理,让我坐那儿 -好啊
- Charlie, let me sit over there. - Yeah, sure.
汤米,怎么了?都没问题吧?
Tommy, what's the matter? Everything's all right?
都没问题
It's all right, yeah.
碰碰手套,上场打拳吧
Touch gloves now, come out boxing.
五秒,艾力克斯
Five seconds, Alex.
站起来...快站起来!
Come on, stand... come on, stand up!
你在干什么? 快打我啊,你这个废物
What the fuck you doin'? Hit me, ya fuckin' bum, come on.
来啊
Come on.
你在干嘛,杰克?快打他啊!
What are you doin', Jake?! Come on, box him!
你是哪根筋不对劲?
What the fuck's the matter with you?
你以为你是来干嘛的?
What do you think you're doin' out there?!
-啊? -他只是动作有点慢
- Huh? - Little slow, that's all.
-你是来干嘛的? -别激动,他可以的
- What are you doin' out there? - Take it easy, he'll be all right.
他慢了点,他会跟上的 你担心个什么劲?
He's a little slow. He'll make it up, what are ya worried about?
妈的,打起精神,杰克,对不起
Goddamn it. Come on, pick it up a little, Jake, I'm sorry.
拜托,杰克,我在你身上下了注!
Come on, Jake, I got some money on ya!
-挡啊! -还手啊,废物!
- Tank job! - Hit him back, ya bum!
-快点 -还手啊!
- Come on. - Hit him back!
你这个废物! 你在第四局就放弃啦?
You fuckin' bum! You're takin' a dive in the fourth?
你一定被收买了!
Pocket your dirty money!
你这个骗子! 这是设计好的!
Aw, you phony bastard! That's a fix!
我们要停止比赛!
We're stoppin' the fight!
干嘛等这么久才停止比赛,混蛋?!
What the fuck are you waitin' for to stop the fight, ya jerk?!
你就站着不动
And you standin' there.
-你下来吧 -裁判在第四局
- Fuckin' go down, will ya? - The referee stops this bout
进行两分又二十三秒时停止比赛
at 2:23 of the fourth round.
技术性击倒的胜利者
The winner by technical knockout,
依然是不败的
and still undefeated,
比利法克斯!
Billy Fox!
我在搞什么?!
What'd I do?!
别再比赛了
Don't fight anymore.
没人逼你,别再比赛了
It's a free country, don't fight anymore.
我在搞什么?我在搞什么?
Aw, what'd I do? What'd I do?
我在搞什么?
What'd I do?
-滚出去! -杰克要接受访问...
- Get outta here! - Jake has an interview...
没关系,杰克,没关系
It's all right, Jake. It's all right.
我为什么那么做?为什么?
Why did I do it? Why?
日报 委员会让拉莫塔停赛
他们有种,真有种
They got some balls, some balls.
我都输了,他们还要怎么样?
I take the dive. What more do they want?
他们要我被击倒在地吗?
They want me to go down, too?
我绝不倒下,我不会为任何人倒下
I ain't goin' down. I ain't goin' down for nobody.
你帮个忙好不好?把手举起来
Why don't you do me a favor? Just put your hands up.
我示范一下,你把手举起来
I wanna show you somethin'. Put your hands up.
-这样做有这么难吗? -你不懂啦
- What the fuck is so hard about that? - Hey, you don't understand.
我得和废物比赛,他是个废物
I had to fight a bum. He's a bum.
我和他比过 我碰他一下,他就不行了
I fought the guy, I tapped him like that, all of a sudden he's like this
东倒西歪的,我能怎么办?
all over the place, what am I gonna do?
你不必帮他,拉他一把
You don't have to fuckin' pick him up and help him.
不拉他一把,我还能怎么办?
What am I gonna do? If I don't pick him up,
我还能怎么办? 我会麻烦更大
then what am I gonna do? I'm gonna be in worse trouble.
我不知道
I don't know.
“奖金扣押”...你看...“奖金扣押”
"Purse was withheld..." look at this... "Purse was withheld pending
“等候检察官调查” 你看看
D.A.'s probe." Look at that.
你看他们让我多难看
Look how they make me look.
像个废物,像个傻瓜
Like a bum, like a mammalucco.
什么?
A what?
像个年度大傻瓜
Like the mammalucco of the year.
汤米不会忘记我们的
Tommy ain't gonna forget us.
只要他不死掉 你可以进入冠军赛
You're gonna get your shot, as long as he don't die.
-只要谁不死? -汤米
- As long as who don't die? - Tommy.
你在说什么?
What are you talkin' about?
换句话说,汤米不会忘了你
In other words, Tommy ain't gonna forget ya,
只要他不死,你就能参赛
you're gonna get your shot if he don't die.
-要保住这家伙的命 -他生病了吗?
- Gotta make sure the guy stays alive. - He got a disease or somethin'?
没有,我只是说说,开玩笑
No, I'm just sayin', I'm kiddin', like.
他怎么了?他有什么毛病吗?
What's wrong with him? Is somethin' wrong with him?
他没有毛病 我是说你一定能打进去
There ain't nothin' wrong with him, that's the only way you wouldn't get it
-除非他死了,不然... -你干嘛说这种话?
- is if he dies, he won't be able to... - What are you talkin' like that for?
两年后 底特律1949年6月15日
中量级冠军 马赛瑟顿
挑战者 杰克拉莫塔
欢迎光临
你要我怎样?这是户外体育场
What do you want me to do? It's an outdoor arena.
你想在雨中比赛吗? 这是体育场
What do you wanna do, fight in the rain? It's a stadium.
你都等这么久了 你可以再等一下
You waited this long, you can wait longer.
你想等二十四小时吗? 我可不想等二十四小时
You wanna wait 24 hours? I don't wanna wait no 24 hours.
我也不想 可是我们不得不等,喂?
I don't either, but we gotta, so we'll wait. Hello?
-你们可不可以住嘴? -不要和他们讲电话
- You guys wanna stop now? - Get off the phone with them.
你干嘛让他们称心如意?
Why do you give them the satisfaction?
-别和他们讲电话了! -他不想和任何人说话
- Get off the phone with them! - He don't wanna talk to nobody.
要跟你讲几次才行? 你没听到他在骂吗?
How many times do we have to tell ya? You hear him yellin'?
这里已经够混乱了 拜托别再打来了
There's enough confusion up here. Please, don't call.
无可奉告,对 谢谢,再见!
No comment. Right. Thank you. Bye!
真讨厌,真不敢相信
Pains in the asses, I don't believe them.
你干嘛让他们称心如意? 干嘛不挂他们电话?
Why do you give them the satisfaction? Why don't you just hang up on 'em?
-挂了就好 -我要吃点东西
- That's all. - I'm gonna get somethin' to eat.
-你想吃什么? -我不想吃
- What do you want to eat? - I don't want nothin'.
我不想吃
I don't want nothin'.
吃嘛,你得吃东西
Eat somethin', you gotta eat somethin'.
你不能不吃东西,吃块牛排
You can't go without eatin'. Eat a steak.
嚼一嚼再吐出来 体重不会在明天增加的
You chew it, you spit it out, you'll still make the weight tomorrow.
你在担心这个吗?
You're worried about that?
我点一块牛排 你想吃的话就可以吃
I'll order a steak. At least if you want it, it's here.
不想吃就把它处理掉
You don't want it, do whatever you want with it.
-点啊 -维琪,你要什么?
- Go ahead. - Vickie, what do you want?
帮我点一块蛋糕
Order me a piece of cake.
你只想吃一块蛋糕?
That's all you want is a piece of cake?
怎么不点起司汉堡和薯条? 对你的身体比较好
Why don't you get a cheeseburger, French fries? It's better for you.
-比较像一顿饭嘛 -好,可以
- It's like a whole meal. - Yeah, that's good.
可以,帮我点一份
That's good, order me one of those.
等一下,你想吃什么?
Wait a minute, what do you want to eat?
你什么时候开始听别人的了?
Since when did you order one of those?
-那是我想吃的 -这是自由国家
- That's what I want. - It's a free country.
你点你想吃的,不要让别人左右你
You order what you want. Don't let nobody influence you.
我没有管她吃什么,我只是提议
I'm not tellin' her what to eat, I was just suggesting.
你干嘛管她该点什么?
What are you tellin' her what to ask for?
我没有管她... 我根本不鸟她吃什么
I'm not tellin' her... personally, I don't give a fuck what she eats.
你干嘛跟她说那些?
What were you tellin' her that for?
帮我点个起司汉堡
Order me a cheeseburger.
帮她点个起司汉堡就好
Just order her a cheeseburger, that's all.
搞什么?
What the f?
你们怎么弄这么久? 这要花多久时间?
What are you guys doin' so long? How long does this thing take to do?
四十秒
Forty seconds.
四十秒不行,得在三十秒内弄完
Forty seconds is no good. You gotta do it in 30 seconds.
缝合伤口的时间就只有这么多
If we gotta stitch him up, that's how much time.
你醒了吗?
Ya up?
-干嘛? -有人来找你
- What? - Somebody's here to see ya.
-嘿,杰克 -嘿,汤米,你好吗?
- Hey, Jack. - Hey, Tommy, how you doin'?
你好吗?
How are you?
和查理打个招呼,查理!
Say hello to Charlie. Charlie!
-杰克,你好吗?祝你好运 -查理,真高兴看到你
- Jake, how are ya? Lots of luck. - Hello, Charlie, good to see you.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你的心情如何? -心情很好,谢谢
- How you feeling? - I'm feelin' all right, thank you.
-心情还好吧? -我会保持愉快心情
- Are you feeling good? - I feel as good as I'm gonna feel.
我得先上场比赛 然后就知道有什么心情了
I gotta get in there and fight, then I'll know how I'm gonna feel.
好,我们只是来祝你好运
All right. We just come by to wish you luck and all that.
-谢谢 -你需要什么吗?
- Thanks. - You need anything?
-没有 -你确定?
- No. - You sure, nothing?
不用,汤米,谢谢
No, thank you, Tommy.
好吧,保重,祝你好运
All right. Take care, good luck.
-上帝保佑 -好,汤米,谢谢
- God bless ya. - All right, thank you.
-你没问题的 -是啊,我没问题
- You'll be all right. - Yeah, I'll be all right.
大家待会见了
See you later, everybody.
-维琪,再见 -汤米,等一下
- Vickie, good-bye. - Tommy, wait.
我想告诉你 我们很感激你来看我们
We really appreciate your comin', I want you to know that.
你真有心,谢谢了
It was really nice of you. I appreciate it.
-好了,乔伊,别客气 -这种时候对他非常重要
- Come on, Joey, anytime. - A time like this is very important to him.
-别客气 -我只是想跟你说再见
- Anytime. - I just wanted to say good-bye.
再见,甜心 好好照顾那家伙好吗?
So long, honey. I want you to take good care of that guy, all right?
-我会照顾他 -乔伊,有任何状况
- I'll take care of him. - Joey, any little thing,
就打电话给我 就连他紧张一下也打电话来
I want you to call me. He's very nervous. Ba-boom, call.
再见,甜心
Good-bye, honey.
你看看那张脸蛋,真美啊
Would you look at that face? What a face.
真令人不敢相信
Can you believe that girl?
看看这个美女,永远那么美
Look at that beauty. Just as beautiful as ever.
-注意所有的状况好吗? -再见,汤米
- The least little thing, all right? - Bye-bye, Tommy.
-大家再见了 -再见,汤米
- So long, everybody. - So long, Tommy.
嘿!过来
Hey! Come here.
过来一下
Come here a minute.
刚才是怎么回事?
What was all that about?
什么?
All what?
你知道我在说什么? 那是怎么回事?
You know what I'm talkin' about. What was that all about?
-和他那样 -没什么,我只是道再见
- With him. - Nothin', I just said good-bye.
你突然间对他这么友善?
All of a sudden you're so friendly with him?
-我只是说声再见 -不是那样做
- I just said good-bye. - You don't do that.
你说哈跟再见就好 听到了没?
You say hello, you say good-bye, that's all, ya hear?
-听到了 -嘿!
- I hear. - Hey!
你听到我的话没? 你要尊重我
You hear what I said? You don't ever have any disrespect for me.
你听到我的话没?
You hear what I said?
-听到了 -好,给我进去
- Yeah, I hear. - All right. Go in there.
-过来 -你别那样好不好?
- Come here. - Why don't you stop that?
你给我闭嘴!闭嘴!
Shut up, you! Shut up!
闭嘴!待会再来跟你算帐!
Shut up! I'll fuckin' take care of you later!
闭嘴!
Shut up!
你们两个让我想吐
Disgusted with the two of youse.
待会再跟你们算帐
Get to youse later.
我是老大,我是老大...
I'm the boss, I'm the boss...
用力打啊,快点!
Hit the fuckin' thing, come on!
好了,走吧
All right, let's go.
祝你好运,杰克!
Good luck, Jake!
杰克
中量级世界冠军赛 共有十五局赛
For the Middleweight Championship of the World, 15 rounds.
一边是非常杰出的挑战者
In this corner, the very worthy challenger,
体重一百五十八又四分一磅
weighing in at 1581/4 pounds,
布朗克斯公牛 杰克拉莫塔!
the Bronx Bull, Jake La Motta!
握个手,铃响就开始比赛
Shake hands, come out fighting at the bell.
拉莫塔对中量级冠军马赛瑟登 底特律1949年
第三局 布里格斯体育场
宰了他!
Kill him!
第七局 布里格斯体育场
压力,给他压力!
Pressure, pressure, pressure!
第九局 布里格斯体育场
把他解决掉 他已经神智不清了,你稳赢
Now finish him off. He's all stupiada, you got him.
加油,杰克!
Come on, Jake!
给他一拳,他会立刻倒地的
Blow on him, he'll fuckin' fall right over for ya.
你看他,你还好吧?
Look at him. Do you feel all right?
-不行啦? -不能继续了?
- No way, huh? - Can't continue?
委员?来一下,我要停止比赛
Hey, Commissioner? Come on in, I'm gonna stop the fight.
你成功了,杰克!
Yeah, you did it, Jake!
各位女士先生请注意
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention, please?
瑟登无法继续比赛 裁判宣布停赛
Cerdan, unable to continue, the referee stops the fight.
技术性击倒的胜利者
And the winner by a technical knockout
在第十局出现
in the tenth round,
新的中量级世界冠军
and the new Middleweight Champion of the World,
布朗克斯公牛 杰克拉莫塔!
the Bronx Bull, Jake La Motta!
杰克!杰克!杰克!杰克!
Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake!
佩尔汉大道 纽约1950年
不要摇它 不要那样摇它,我告诉你
Don't shake that. Don't shake it like that, I'm tellin' ya.
那是最糟的做法
It's the worst thing you could do.
哦,你在家
Oh, you're home.
-嗨,维琪 -嗨,乔
- Hi, Vick. - Hi, Joe.
-哈 -嗨,你去哪了?
- Hello. - Hi. Where were ya?
出去了,怎么回事?
I went out. What's the matter?
电视不能看
Television won't work.
你去哪里?
Where'd you go?
出去,去血拼,去我妹那儿嘛
Went out, went shoppin'. Went to my sister's. You know.
你是怎么搞的? 干嘛亲她的嘴?
What's the matter with you? What's with this kissin' on the mouth?
我只是打个招呼 我不能亲我的大嫂吗?
I just said hello. Can't I kiss my sister-in-law?
亲脸颊还不够吗?
Isn't the cheek good enough for you?
别这样好吗?
Come on, huh?
我就不会像你亲她那样 亲老妈的嘴
I don't even kiss Mom on the mouth the way you kiss her.
突然间,你成了大情圣
All of a sudden, you're like a Romeo.
你本来就不该亲妈妈的嘴
You're not supposed to kiss your mother on the mouth.
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm talkin' about.
-怎么样? -好像有东西了
- How's that? - That looks like somethin'.
后退点,你的肚子挡到看不到
Get back, I can't see nothin' with your stomach in the way.
你干嘛瞪我?
What are you givin' me dirty looks for?
你是个冠军,却没命地狂吃
Supposed to be a champion, ya eat like there's no tomorrow.
尽管吃吧... 你忘了你等多久
That's it, go ahead... forget how long it took you
才进入冠军赛,多年来的辛苦
to get to the title, all the years, the hard work.
你都忘了 你下个月要卫冕赛,你还吃
You forgot. You're gonna defend it next month, keep eatin'.
还瞪我,好像我胡言乱语似的
Give me dirty looks like I don't know what I'm talkin' about?
你在柯帕酒吧 和沙维是怎么回事?
What happened with you and Salvy at the Copa that time?
-什么时候? -你痛扁他那次
- When? - When you gave him a beatin'.
你是说我用计程车门撞他的头
You mean when I caught his head in the taxicab door,
还用玻璃打他那次?
and was bangin' it, smacked him with a glass?
-对 -我跟你讲过了
- Yeah. - I told you about that.
-没有吗? -没有
- Didn't I? - No.
-我没跟你说过? -没有,你没说过
- I never told you? - No, you never told me.
反正没什么大不了的
It was no big thing, anyway.
我打他的嘴 他喝醉了,开始打起来
I smacked him in the mouth, he was drunk, he started some shit.
还得去市区和汤米解决这件事
Had to go downtown, straighten it all out with Tommy.
反正现在已经没事了
It's all forgotten about, supposedly, anyway.
你怎么没跟我说过?
How come you never told me about it?
那件事又和你无关
It didn't have anything to do with you.
-和我无关? -对啊
- Had nothin' to do with me? - No.
那和谁有关...维琪吗?
Who'd it have somethin' to do with... Vickie?
我不是才跟你解释了整件事吗?
I just explained the whole thing to you, didn't I?
-对 -那是我和沙维的事
- Yeah. - It was between me and Salvy.
如果是和你或维琪有关 我会告诉你的
If it had anything to do with you and Vickie, I woulda told you about it.
我听到的不是这样,乔
That's not what I heard, Joe.
什么叫你听到的不是这样?
What do you mean, that's not what you heard?
-我听到的不是这样 -你听到什么?
- That's not what I heard. - What'd you hear?
我听到一些传言
I heard some things.
-你听说我和沙维... -我听到传言,乔伊
- You heard about me and Salvy... - I heard things, Joey.
你听说我痛扁沙维一顿吧 你听说什么?
You heard that I cracked Salvy all around, what'd you hear?
-我听到传言 -你听到什么?
- I heard things. - What things you heard?
我听到传言
I heard some things.
你听到传言,你又想担心? 别又开始做怪了
You heard things. You wanna worry? Don't start that shit.
你知道你该担心什么?
You know what you should worry about?
担心下个月的冠军赛吧 那才是你该担心的事
Worry you got this title fight next month. That's what you should worry about.
担心那个吧
Do that.
老天!
Christ!
-沙维有上维琪吗? -什么?
- Did Salvy fuck Vickie? - What?
沙维有上维琪吗?
Did Salvy fuck Vickie?
杰克,别又开始了
Hey, Jack, don't start your shit.
-真的,不要那样 -乔伊,我问你话
- No, really, don't start. - Joey, I asked ya.
-我不是叫你盯着她吗? -我有盯着她啊
- Didn't I ask ya to keep an eye on her? - And I did keep an eye on her.
那你干嘛扁他一顿?
Then how come ya gave him a beatin'?
我说了,我说过是怎么回事
I told you that. I told you what that was all about.
完全和你无关
Didn't have nothin' to do with you.
-他自以为了不起... -乔伊,不要骗我
- He thinks he's a wiseguy... - Joey, don't lie to me.
-我没有骗你 -我看来像笨蛋吗?
- I'm not lyin'. - What do I look like to you?
嘿,我是你弟弟
Hey, I'm your brother.
你应该相信我的 你不信任我吗?
You're supposed to believe me. Don't you trust me?
-对,不信任 -是吗?谢了
- No, I don't. - You don't? That's nice.
有她在,我就不信任你 我不信任任何人
I don't trust you when it comes to her. I don't trust nobody.
-告诉我发生了什么事 -我跟你说过是怎么回事
- Tell me what happened. - I told you exactly what happened.
他太过份,我就扁他一顿
He got out of line, I slapped him around.
汤米都解决了 事情过去了
Tommy straightened it all out, and it's all over.
你有那个表情,乔伊
You give me that look, Joey.
我不得不接受你的回答,懂吗?
I gotta accept your answer, you know?
但是我告诉你 如果给我听到什么
But I'm tellin' ya now, if I hear anything,
我用老妈发誓,我会杀人的
I swear on our mother, I'm gonna kill somebody.
-我会杀人的 -把每个人都杀掉算了!
- I'm gonna kill somebody. - Well, go ahead and kill everybody!
你是硬汉,去杀啊
You're the tough guy, go kill people.
杀掉维琪,沙维,汤米
Kill Vickie, kill Salvy, kill Tommy Como,
干脆也把我杀掉算了
kill me, while you're at it, what do I care?
你根本就是在自杀 吃成那样,你这个妈的肥猪!
You're killin' yourself, the way you eat, ya fat fuck!
-你看看你! -什么意思?
- Look at ya! - What do you mean?
我不明白,什么意思,杀了你?
I don't understand, what do you mean, kill you?
杀了我啊!从这儿开始! 先杀了我,帮我个它妈的忙!
Me, kill me! Start here! Kill me first, do me a fuckin' favor!
因为你快把我搞疯了!
'Cause you're drivin' me crazy!
你是个杀手,大人物 来杀啊,你这个杀手
You're a killer, you're a big shot. Just kill, you're a killer.
对不起,你为什么说到你呢?
Excuse me, what do you mean by you, though?
怎样?什么意思? 没有什么意思
So? What does that mean? Don't mean nothin'.
你自己都不知道为什么说到自己
Even you don't know what you meant by you.
-没什么意思 -乔伊,一定有什么含意
- Don't mean nothin'. - Joey, that meant somethin'.
你提到汤米,沙维,还提到你...
You mentioned Tommy, Salvy, you mentioned you...
你把你和他们归在一类
you included you with them.
你可以提到任何人 但是你说你和他们
You coulda said anybody, but you said you and them.
你真的被这个女人毁了 看看你自己
You really let this girl ruin your life, look at ya.
她真的把你搞疯了 你知道你有多它妈的神经吗?
She really did some job on ya, ya know how fuckin' nuts you are?
-你看她把你搞成这样! -你有上我老婆吗?
- Look what she did to you! - You fuck my wife?
-什么? -你上我老婆
- What?! - You fuck my wife?
你竟然问我这种问题?
How could you ask me a question like that?
你怎么问得出来?我是你弟
How could you ask me? I'm your brother.
你竟然问我?
You ask me that?
你怎么有胆敢问我这种问题?
Where do you get your balls big enough to ask me that?
告诉我
Just tell me.
我才不要回答
I'm not answerin' that.
我不回答那种问题,太愚蠢了
I'm not gonna answer that, it's stupid.
你真聪明,乔伊
You're very smart, Joey.
你说了一堆,却不给我正确的答案
You're givin' me all these answers, but you ain't givin' me the right answer.
我再问你一次
I'm gonna ask ya again.
你有还是没有?
Did you or did you not?
我不要回答
I'm not gonna answer.
那个问题有病,你也有它妈的病
That's a sick question, you're a sick fuck,
我没有病,所以我不要回答
and I'm not that sick that I'm gonna answer it.
我不要跟你说话,我要走了
I'm not tellin' ya anything. I'm gonna leave.
如果莉诺打来,就说我回家了 我不要待在这个疯人院
If Lenore calls, tell her I went home. I'm not stayin' in this nuthouse with ya.
你还真有病... 我真的很同情你
You're a sick bastard... I feel sorry for ya, I really do.
你知道你该怎么做?
You know what you should do?
多做点爱,少吃点东西
Try a little more fuckin' and a little less eatin'.
你就不会有闺房的问题了
You won't have troubles upstairs in your bedroom,
你也不会找我或其他人出气了
and you won't pick it out on me and everybody else.
懂不懂,神经病? 你快它妈的崩溃了
Ya understand, ya fuckin' wacko? You're crackin' up.
它妈的神经病
Fuckin' screwball, ya.
你去哪里了?
Where were ya?
我在我妹那儿
I was at my sister's.
然后你去了哪里?
Where'd you go after that?
-看电影 -看了什么电影?
- To the movies. - Yeah, what'd you see?
“岳父大人”
Father of the Bride.
你怎么没跟我说柯帕酒吧的事?
How come you didn't tell me about the Copa?
-要跟你说什么? -你知道的
- Tell you what about it? - You know.
你怎么没跟我说?
How come you didn't tell me about it?
你为什么没跟我说,嗯?
Why didn't you tell me about it, huh?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
你为什么没说? 你有上我弟弟吗?
Why didn't you tell me? Did you fuck my brother?
-放开我,你这只肥猪! -有没有?有没有?
- Get off me, you fat pig! - Did you? Did you?
-啊? -没有!
- Huh? - No!
把门打开
Open the door.
-走开! -快把门打开
- Get away! - Come on, open the door.
-我想跟你说话 -滚远点,你有病!
- I wanna talk to you. - Get away from me, you're sick!
我只想问你一件事 你为什么上乔伊?
I just wanna ask you one thing. Why'd you fuck Joey?
-滚开! -把门打开
- Get away! - Open the door.
不要
No.
为什么?为什么那么做?
Why'd you do it? Why'd you do it, huh?
我什么也没做!
I didn't do anything!
-你为什么上他们? -做什么?我什么也没做!
- Why did you fuck them? - Do what? I didn't do anything?!
他们我全都上了!
I fucked all of 'em!
-你要我说什么? -什么意思,你上了谁?
- What do you want me to say? - What do you mean, who'd you fuck?
我上了所有的人... 汤米,沙维,你弟弟,全部!
I fucked all of 'em... Tommy, Salvy, your brother, all of 'em!
你还替你弟口交! 你要我说什么?
I sucked your brother's cock! What do you want me to say?!
-你替他口交? -我替他口交
- You sucked his cock? - I sucked his cock,
还有这条街上的每个人
and everybody else on the fuckin' street.
你想怎样? 你只是个臃肿自私的笨蛋!
What do you want? You're nothin' but a fat pig, selfish fool!
你去死吧!
Forget fuckin' with you!
他的老二还比你的大!
His fuckin' cock's bigger than yours, too!
你要去哪里?
Where you goin'?
你要去哪里,混帐?
Where are you goin', you bastard?
你这个变态!你要去哪里?
You sick animal! Where you goin'?
放开我!放开我,杂碎!
Let me go! Get off of me, ya piece of shit!
如果我再看到你用手碰盘子
If I see you put your hands in that plate one more time,
我就用这把刀刺你,听到没?
I'm gonna stab you with this knife, ya hear me?
我叫你不要用手吃东西!
I told ya, keep your hands outta the plate!
我们为什么不能 安静吃饭?别激动
Why can't we eat in peace around here? Just relax.
我得和你一样吗?像个野人...
Do I have to eat like you? Like a gavone, like...
杰克!杰克!你怎么了?!
Jack! Jack! What's the matter with you?!
你上我老婆是不是?!
Ya fucked my wife, huh?!
放开他!
Get off of him!
-我杀了你!我杀了你! -住手,他没有!
- I'll kill ya! I'll kill ya! - Stop it, he didn't do it!
快报警!
Call the police!
我要杀了你!
I'll fuckin' kill ya!
出去!
Get out!
不要走,甜心,求求你
Don't leave, honey, please.
甜心...没有你和孩子 我就什么也不是,不要走
Honey, look... I'm a bum without you and the kids, don't go.
只是...
Just...
只剩不到一分钟 拉莫塔就快要失去
Less than a minute to go, and La Motta is losing the title
他打败马赛瑟登 而赢来的冠军头衔
that he won from the gallant Marcel Cerdan.
在瑟登不幸坠机身亡之后
After the tragic plane crash that took Cerdan's life,
罗伦道惠誓言 要为法国赢回冠军头衔
Laurent Dauthuille vowed to bring the title back to France.
今晚,他只须撑过这第十五局
Tonight, he only has to last this fifteenth round
就可以成为新的中量级冠军
to be crowned the new Middleweight Champion.
拉莫塔被道惠逼到绳索旁痛殴
La Motta is taking terrible punishment on the ropes as Dauthuille bangs him
左右开攻他的头部 左拳右拳打中下巴
with lefts and rights to the head. Another left, another right to the jaw.
拉莫塔反守为攻 他一直是在装死!
La Motta turns around, he's been playing possum!
他狠狠教训道惠! 他的右拳重击身体
He's got Dauthuille hurt! He rips a right hand to the body,
下巴打了两记左勾拳 左右开攻头部!
two left hooks to the jaw, another left and a right to the head!
道惠被打得团团转!
Dauthuille is reeling around the ring!
毫无疑问,情势扭转了!
The tide has turned, no question about it!
他晃到绳索旁倒下了!
And he wobbles into the ropes and goes down!
道惠倒下了 裁判路汉勒跑过来
Dauthuille is down, and referee Lou Handler comes over
他开始计时 他试着爬起来
and starts the count. He's trying to get up.
六...七...
Six... seven...
他爬不起来的 九...十!
He'll never make it. Nine... ten!
出局!
You're out!
比赛结束!
It is all over!
他被击倒了,比赛只剩十三秒
He is knocked out, and Jake La Motta,
杰克拉莫塔在最后一局
with 13 seconds left to go in the final round,
出人意外地卷土重来
has made one of the most remarkable comebacks
-拳击史上少见 -杰克拉莫塔!
- in all boxing history. - Jake La Motta!
来吧
Come on.
就跟他说对不起,你想念他
Just tell him you're sorry, you miss him.
他是你弟弟 你迟早要跟他说话的
He's your brother, you have to talk to him sooner or later.
我先替你接通,然后你跟他说
I'll dial him for you, then you talk to him.
跟他说对不起 然后你就可以聊别的了
Just tell him you're sorry, then you can say whatever you want.
你打吧
Go ahead.
冠军,我想问你几个问题
Hey, champ... like to ask you a few questions.
-现在不行 -我等了你一个小时了
- Not now. - I been waitin' an hour for you.
-抱歉,我老婆在... -这个立场很棒...
- Excuse me, my wife is... - There's a great angle here...
请不要打扰我,走开
Don't bother me, please. Get outta here.
拜托嘛,冠军?
Come on. All right, champ?
-你是大好人 -我好好跟你说了
- You're a great guy. - I asked you nice, will ya?
喂?
Hello?
沙维,这一点也不好笑
Salvy, this ain't funny anymore.
是你吗?
Is that you?
我知道那一头有人 我听到你的呼吸声
I know somebody's there, I can hear you breathin'.
你在听吗?
You listenin'?
你妈专门替大象口交
Your mother sucks fuckin' big fuckin' elephant dicks.
听到了没?
You got that?
他不在家
真是年度大赛
The fight of the year.
下次酒保问你喝什么的话
The next time that friendly bartender says, "What'll you have?"
告诉他全世界的口头禅 “就是要蓝带”
Give him that answer the whole world gives, "Pabst Blue Ribbon."
拉莫塔的拳正中要害
Those punches by La Motta explain themselves.
他们在1942年 和1945年间对打五次
They fought five times between 1942 and 1945.
目前是场激烈的中量级冠军赛
It has so far been a blazing bout for the Middleweight Championship.
拉莫塔的表现优异 却无法获得高分
In that great action by La Motta, he couldn't score the big one.
那是他的最后机会了
That's it, that was his last shot.
第十三局,不吉利的数字
Round number 13, the hard-luck number.
铃声响了
There's the buzzer,
你们都知道参赛者是谁
and I think you know both the boys.
罗宾森痛击拉莫塔 他现在让他好看
Robinson hurting La Motta, he's hurting him now.
他把拉莫塔逼到死角去了
He has La Motta on queer street, holding on.
当然这是你近年来见过
Certainly, that was one of the most damaging evidences
破坏力最强的拳了
of punching that you have seen in recent years.
来啊!来啊
Come on! Come on.
-你站在那儿干嘛? -显然疲累的罗宾森
- What are you standin' there for? - Robinson, apparently tired,
击出完美的一拳 打得杰克拉莫塔
punched with a "fare thee well," and rocked Jake La Motta
-天摇地动 -来啊,来啊!
- right to his heels. - Come on, Ray, come on!
这几拳干净俐落
These are clean, whistling shots.
不知道他如何能屹立不倒
How he can survive them, nobody knows.
没有人能承受这些重拳!
No man can endure this pummeling!
在法兰奇西柯拉的指示下...
The fight is stopped on...
比赛停下来
the signal to Frankie Sikora.
场外所有的观众
Row after row after row from the ring,
都站起来欢呼
the crowd is standing and cheering,
他炮轰了杰克拉莫塔
as he just cannonaded Jake La Motta
-让他彻底败退 -罗宾森
- into a death defeat. - Hey, Ray.
这时候杰克还不想放弃
And when I say that, I mean Jake wouldn't want to quit.
-他还想再打 -罗宾森
- He wanted to go. - Hey, Ray.
我没倒下,罗宾森
Never went down, Ray.
你从没把我打倒过
You never got me down, Ray.
你听到没?
Ya hear me?
从没把我打倒过
Never got me down.
有没有看到?
Yeah? See, look?
在不吉利的第十三局
And in the thirteenth round, the hard-luck round,
世界冠军换人了
the championship of the world has changed hands.
你看到了...
And there you see it...
上届冠军已败退
a champion gone down to defeat.
现在我们在等候赛场广播员
And so, now we wait for the announcement
艾迪佛林宣布结果
from Eddie Flint, the ring announcer.
然后我们就会上场,和全世界
Then we'll get up in the ring, join with the radio audience
收音机旁的听众
throughout the world,
一起访问罗宾森
and have a brief interview with Ray Robinson.
现在我们在等候宣布
Now we're waiting for the time to be announced.
委员将结果交给艾迪佛林
And it is being handed between the commissioner and Eddie Flint.
比赛在乔崔那的指示下停止...
The fight was stopped on a signal from Joe Tryner...
各位先生女士请注意!
Attention, ladies and gentlemen!
在第十三局进行两分四秒后
The winner by a technical knockout in two minutes and four seconds
技术性击倒的胜利者
of the thirteenth round,
以及中量级拳击的新世界冠军
and the new World's Middleweight Boxing Champion,
雷罗宾森!
Sugar Ray Robinson!
迈阿密 1956年
你为什么退出星期三的比赛?
Why are you pulling out of Wednesday's fight?
结束了...我的拳击生涯结束了
It's over for me... boxing's over for me.
我不打了
I'm through.
我受够了成天担心体重
I'm tired of worryin' about weight.
我以前满脑子只想着体重
That's all I used to think about was weight, weight, weight.
久了你就明白生命中还有别的事物
After a while, you realize there are other things in life.
我很感激我的拳击生涯
I'm very grateful. Boxing's been good to me.
我有一栋豪宅,有三个好孩子
I got a nice house, I got three great kids.
我有个又美又好的老婆 我还能要求什么?
I got a wonderful, beautiful wife. What more could I ask for?
-你叫什么名字? -巴伯
- Hey, what's your name? - Bob.
照张相吧,巴伯
Take a picture, Bob.
甜心,让他照张相...为了我们
Let him take a picture of ya, honey... for us.
来,笑一个
Go ahead, smile.
谢谢你,巴伯
Thank you, Bob.
照一张全家福 杰克,过来坐在这里
Take a picture of all of us. Jackie, come here, sit over here.
好,大家笑一个
All right, everybody, smile. Smile.
拉莫塔太太 你对杰克退休有什么看法?
Mrs. La Motta, how do you feel about Jake's retirement?
我觉得很棒
I think it's great.
他选择退休的时机很恰当
He picked the right time to stop fightin'.
他现在每天在家陪我们
He's home with us all the time now.
-真的很棒 -你知道吗?你讲完了吗?
- It's really good. - You know what? You through?
-对不起,你讲完了? -对
- Excuse me, you through? - Yeah.
我才在柯林斯大道买了一间俱乐部
I just bought a club on Collins Avenue.
那是一间酒吧加酒店 你猜我要取什么名字?
It's a bar, package store, everything. Guess what I'm gonna call it?
我不知道
I don't know.
-你要取什么名字? -猜一下
- What are you gonna call it? - Take a guess.
杰克拉莫塔酒店
好了,闭嘴 够了,够了
All right, shut up. Enough, enough.
谢谢
Thank you.
只是想看看麦克风
Just wanted to see what the microphone
在美女的身上听来如何
on a sexy girl sounds like.
都听到了吧
See how that sounds.
大家晚安
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
从最后一次 在麦迪森广场花园比赛以来
I haven't seen so many losers since my last fight
我还没见过这么多的废物
at Madison Square Garden.
好了,甜心
Okay, honey.
谢谢,美女
Thank you, doll.
-不得了吧? -再给我们来一杯
- Isn't that somethin'? - Bring us another drink.
-干杯 -干杯
- Salute. - Salute.
看看这个美女
Look at this terrific girl.
她是让你想带回家去 见父亲的那种女孩
She's the kinda girl you wanna bring home to your father,
尤其如果他是变态的话
especially if he's a degenerate.
是我说的吗?
Did I say that?
不,说真的,今天晚上很高兴
Nah, seriously, folks, it's a thrill to be standing here
能站在你们这些美丽的观众面前
before all you wonderful people tonight.
事实上,我很高兴我能站着
In fact, it's a thrill to be standing.
如果你们相信 我很高兴站在你们面前...
If you believe it's a thrill to be standin' before you wonderful people, then...
那你们就是大骗子
you're all full of shit.
对了,我和我老婆维琪要结婚了
By the way, me and my wife Vickie's gettin' married.
我在说什么?我疯了
What am I talkin' about? I'm out of it.
她在吗?她不在
Is she here? She's not here.
维琪? 不,她不在这儿
Vickie? Nah, she's not here.
对了,我和我老婆维琪要庆祝...
By the way, me and my wife Vickie's gonna celebrate...
刚才说错...我们结婚十一年
it's a little different... our 11th wedding anniversary.
谢谢
Thank you.
那让我想起我的两个朋友
That reminds me about two friends of mine.
一个已婚,一个单身
One was married, one was single.
已婚的那个跟单身的说
The married guy tells the single guy,
“你怎么回事?”
"What's the matter with you?
“你怎么回事? 看看我再看看你”
"What's the matter with you? Look at me, and look at you.
“看看我再看看你”
And look at me, and look at you."
让我继续说下去
Let me get on with it.
“我晚上回家就看到我老婆”
"When I come home at night, my wife's at the door
“手里拿着酒等我”
"with a tall drink in her hand.
“然后她让我洗个热水澡”
"Then she gives me a nice hot bath,
“然后她替我按摩”
"then she gives me a nice rubdown,
“然后她激情地和我做爱”
"then she makes passionate love to me,
“然后她做晚餐给我吃”
"and then she makes me a nice dinner.
“真是夫复何求?你该试试”
What more could you ask for? You oughta try that."
另一个朋友说“嘿,听来很棒”
The other friend says, "Hey, that sounds great.
“你老婆几点回家?”
What time does your wife get home?"
我知道我不是奥利维 但如果他和罗宾森对打的话
I know I'm no Olivier, but if he fought Sugar Ray,
他会说
he would say
重点不在于比赛
that the thing ain't the ring,
而在于娱乐
it's the play.
给我一个舞台
So give me a stage
让我这只公牛发威吧
where this bull here can rage,
虽然我可以打斗
and though I can fight,
我宁愿吟诵
I'd much rather hear myself recite.
那才是娱乐!
That's entertainment!
杰克,你好吗?
Jake, how have you been?
嘿!太精彩了
Hey! You were just great.
好在罗宾森今晚没来,对吧?
It's a good thing Sugar Ray wasn't here tonight, huh?
-他上星期讲过这个笑话 -少来!
- He told that joke last week. - Come on!
他老了,不断说一样的话
He repeats himself, gettin' a little senile.
这位是州检察官布朗森
I'd like you to meet State's Attorney Bronson.
-你好吗?很高兴认识你 -他的夫人
- How are ya? Nice to meet you. - And his wife.
-很高兴认识你 -你不该是这星期来吧
- Nice to meet you. - You shouldn't be here this week.
我们是下星期才交保护费,对吧?
It's next week we got the shakedown payments, right?
很高兴见到你
It's good seein' you.
那是开玩笑对不对?
That is a joke, right?
开玩笑的... 只有你才知道是不是玩笑
It's a joke... only you know if it's a joke.
他只是开玩笑吧?
He's just kidding, right?
好,我们待会再讨论
All right, we'll talk about it later.
-这位是尊夫人? -对,布朗森太太
- This is your wife? - Yes, Mrs. Bronson.
很漂亮,真是幸会
Very pretty lady. Charmed to meet you.
-谢谢 -他是个好人
- Thank you. - He's really a nice guy.
你开得起玩笑吧,美女?
You can take a joke, can't you, doll?
-对不起 -没关系
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
嘿,卡罗?卡罗!
Hey, Carlo? Carlo!
再给他们拿酒来 这里出状况了
Give 'em another drink. Somethin' happened over here.
-亲爱的琳达,过来 -尊夫人呢?
- Darling, Linda, come here. - Where's your wife?
-我老婆? -对,为什么她没来?
- My wife? - Yeah, why isn't she here?
关你什么事? 你想我会把她带来
What's it to you? You think I'm gonna bring her around here,
-让你们这些无赖追她吗? -别这样!
- let you bums get involved with her? - Come on!
尤其是州检察官在这儿?
Especially the State's Attorney over here?
他很常来,亲爱的,盯紧他
He comes here a lot, darling, watch him.
他知道我只是开玩笑
He knows I'm only kiddin'.
-谢谢 -盯着他
- Thank you. - Keep an eye on him.
有什么问题?
What's the problem?
没什么大问题
There's really not a problem.
她看来不像二十一岁 所以我请她出示身份证
She doesn't look 21, so I just had to ask for some I.D.
-你几岁,甜心? -二十一岁
- How old are you, honey? - Twenty-one.
-二十一? -嗯
- Twenty-one? - Mm-hmm.
你能证明你二十一岁吗?
Can you prove that you're 21?
-嗯 -证明给我看
- Mm-hmm. - Prove it to me.
这么会接吻的女孩 可以随时来我的店里喝酒
Any girl that can kiss like that can drink at my joint anytime.
你呢?你几岁?
What about you? How old are you?
-二十一岁 -你能证明你二十一岁吗?
- Twenty-one. - Can you prove that you're 21?
-可以 -你可以证明给我看吗?
- Yes. - Would you prove it to me?
过来
Come here.
她也二十一岁吗?
She's 21, too?
我相信她也是二十一岁
She has convinced me that she's 21, too.
-小心,我在倒酒 -你的夫人在外面
- Watch it while I'm pouring. - Your wife's outside.
-她在等你 -怎么不大声一点?
- She's waitin' for you. - Why don't ya tell me a little louder?
好了
There.
拜托,杰克
Come on, Jake.
寂寞的夜
Lonely nights
我好寂寞
I'm so lonely
求你回家
Please come home
你这个亲爱的宝贝
You great big lump of sugar
我好想你
I miss you so much
求你回家
Please come home
寂寞的夜
Lonely nights
昨天晚上很忙
It was a busy night last night.
-一切都好吗? -我要离开你,杰克
- Everything all right? - I'm leaving you, Jake.
-讲点新鲜的 -不,我这次是说真的
- What else is new? - No. I mean it this time.
我不想在把事情办好之前告诉你
I didn't wanna tell you till I had everything worked out.
-过去 -干嘛?
- Move over. - Why?
-好让你来打我吗? -开门
- So you can put your hands on me? - Open the door.
甜心,开门嘛
Come on, honey, open the door.
我找了律师,我要离婚
I got a lawyer, we're gettin' a divorce
我还要孩子的监护权
and I'm gettin' custody of the kids.
-让我进来一下 -不要,我已经决定了
- Let me in for a minute. - No, I already made up my mind.
我要离开,就是这样
I'm leavin'. That's it.
孩子会跟我,如果你敢出现
Kids are gonna be with me, and if you show your face around,
我就报警
I'm gonna call the cops on you.
-好吗?说完了 -不要那样嘛,甜心
- All right? That's it. - Don't act that way, honey.
快点,杰克,醒一醒
Come on, champ. Come on, wake up.
醒一醒,杰克
Wake up, champ.
什么事?
What's up?
-检察官派我们来 -我知道你们是谁
- We're from the D.A. - Yeah, I know where you're from.
-他们想和你谈谈 -你们看来都一个样子
- They wanna talk with you. - Youse all look the same to me.
-有什么差别? -他们想和你谈谈
- What's the difference? - They wanna talk with you.
-谈什么? -我不知道,我不是上级
- About what? - I don't know, I don't run the joint.
-他们只叫我来带你回去 -可是你们想干嘛?
- They just told me to bring you in. - But what do youse want?
为了什么?
For what?
你认得这个女孩吗?
Do you recognize this girl?
她去过俱乐部吗?
She been in the club?
-这是同一个女孩子? -对
- This is the same girl? - Yeah.
不,我不认识她
Nah, I don't know her.
她说你介绍她认识一些男人
She says you introduced her to some men.
我介绍她认识男人 我介绍很多人认识
I introduced her to men. I introduce a lot of people to a lot of people.
你说我介绍她认识男人 我也介绍他认识男人啊
You tell me I introduced her to men. I introduced him to men.
可是我没什么好说的
But I don't say nothin'.
她才十四岁 穿上鞋子吧,杰克
She's 14. Come on, put on your shoes, Jake.
-她几岁? -十四岁
- She's how old? - Fourteen.
她十四岁? 让我看一下
She's 14? Let me see that.
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you somethin'.
你认为这个女孩看来像十四岁吗?
You gonna tell me that that girl looks 14?
-她是十四岁 -我用男人的角度问你
- She's 14. - I'm gonna ask you man to man.
我能说什么?我们走吧
What am I gonna say? Come on, we gotta go.
-我们得去市中心? -没错
- We gotta go downtown? - That's right.
为什么,因为这个女孩子?
For what, because of this girl?
-你喝醉了吗? -开门,我在保释中
- You drunk? - Open the door, I'm out on bail.
我只是拿个东西就走,我保证
I just gotta pick up one thing and I'll leave, I promise.
-孩子们在睡觉 -我不会吵到他们
- Kids are sleepin'. - I won't bother them.
让我拿个东西就好
Let me just get somethin'.
好,不要出声
All right, don't make no noise.
-什么? -不要出声
- What? - Don't make no noise.
不会的,我只是来拿这个东西
I won't, I just gotta get this one thing.
-你在做什么? -我得筹一万块
- What are you doin'? - I gotta get $10,000.
我的律师说 只要花个一万块贿赂一下
My lawyer says if I can spread 10,000 around,
-就能让他们彻销告诉 -他们告不了你
- I can get the case dropped. - They don't have a case against you.
是吗?你开玩笑是不是?
Oh, no? You kiddin' me, or what?
你见过十四岁的人在法庭做证吗?
You ever see a 14-year-old testify in court?
你看过报纸了... “拉莫塔因妨害风化罪保释”
You saw the papers... "La Motta Out on Vice Rap."
-你弄腰带做什么? -有什么差别吗?
- What are you doin' to the belt? - What difference does it make?
你不能跟朋友筹到钱吗?
Can't you get the money from your friends?
哪来的朋友?
Yeah, what friends?
你会把我的孩子吵醒的!
You're gonna wake my kids up!
你会吵醒孩子,住手!
You're gonna wake the kids, stop it!
你怎么回事?
What's the matter with you?
你盘子都不会好好放吗?
Don't you put the dishes so they don't fall down?
腰带呢,拉莫塔先生?
What about the belt, Mr. La Motta?
你要卖给我的不是冠军腰带吗?
Isn't that what you wanted to sell me, the championship belt?
-这些是腰带上的珠宝 -可是腰带呢?
- These are the jewels from the belt. - But where's the belt?
冠军腰带是很珍贵的物品
The belt of a champion is a very rare item.
真希望你先来找我谈 拉莫塔先生
I wish you'd come to me in the first place, Mr. La Motta.
腰带和珠宝就不会分家了...
You'd have had the belt and the jewels together...
给我两千块
Give me 2,000 for them.
-给我两千 -顶多一千五...
- Give me 2,000. - 1,500 top, that's all...
-你不能给我两千? -顶多一千五,拉莫塔先生
- You can't give me 2,000? - 1,500 top, Mr. La Motta.
-抱歉,我会赔钱... -还给我
- I'm sorry. I'd lose... - Give me them.
别告诉我你没赚钱
Don't tell me you're not gonna make a profit.
我知道你说谎 我上街卖保证能拿两倍的价钱
I know you're lyin'. Go around the corner, I bet you I get twice what you're offerin'.
我筹不到一万块
I can't raise the 10,000.
我都试过了 我到处都试过了
I tried, I tried. I tried a lot of places.
好,那我要怎么办?
Yeah, but what am I gonna do?
如果他们要那样我也没辄吧?
If that's what they're gonna do, they're gonna do it, what can I do?
去他们的,随便他们要怎样
Then fuck 'em, let 'em do what they're gonna do.
佛罗里达,戴德郡监狱 1957年
给我进牢房去,快点!
Get in the goddamn cell, now, come on!
-没错,不能再伤害人了 -到了,就是这里
- That's right, can't hurt folks no more. - This is where it's at right here.
是谁想逃的啊?
Who was the one goddamn tryin' to shirk, huh?
-你乖乖在这儿吧 -没错
- You'll pull your load here, boy. - That's right.
-我不要了! -你给我进去!
- I don't want no more! - Get in the goddamn box!
看我怎么驯服你,王八蛋!
I'll break you on one of my fuckin' farms, you son of a bitch!
-你听到没? -你去死吧
- Do you hear me? - Go fuck yourself.
先抓着他一下! -好了
- Hold onto him just a minute! - I got it.
看到没?看到没?!
See it? See it?!
你看着!习惯吧!
Look at it, son! Live in it!
去啊,习惯吧!
Go on, boy, live in it!
-你明白吗? -你妈去死!
- Do you understand that? - On your mother's cunt, then!
他妈的...!
Your mother's!
-混蛋! -习惯吧!
- You cocksucker! - Live in it!
叫他坐下,去他的!
Let that son of a bitch sit, fuck him!
去你的!
Fuck you!
去你妈的!
Fuck your mother!
笨蛋,笨蛋,笨蛋...
Dummy, dummy, dummy...
为什么?为什么?为什么?
Why? Why? Why?
你这个混蛋!
You motherfucker!
我的手啊!
My hands!
你为什么那么做?
Why'd you do it, why?
你好笨,你好笨
You're so stupid, you're so stupid,
你真是笨死了!
you're so fuckin' stupid!
你好笨
You're so stupid.
他们骂我是畜牲,我不是畜牲
They called me an animal. I'm not an animal.
我不是畜牲
I'm not an animal.
他们为什么这样对我? 我没那么坏,我没那么坏
Why do they treat me like this? I'm not that bad. I'm not that bad.
我不是坏人
I'm not that guy.
他回家发现他老婆 和别的男人在床上,老婆说
Guy comes home, finds his wife in bed with another guy, the wife says,
“你看谁来了...大嘴巴 现在大家都会知道了”
"Look who's here... big mouth. Now the whole neighborhood will know."
纽约市 1958年
谢谢你们大笑 大家开心一下
Thanks. Thanks for laughin'. Spread it around a little bit.
在这儿的第一晚 我问这儿的老板
The first night I was here, I said to the owner of the joint,
我说“厕所在哪里?”
I said, "Listen, where's the toilet?"
他说“你就在里面”
He said, "You're in it."
走了,咱们走了
Come on, let's go, let's go.
你们别烦我,我只是在上班
Why don't you leave me alone? I'm tryin' to do my routine.
去你的
Up yours.
老兄,你会逼我复出打拳的
Pal, you're gonna force me to make a comeback.
-好笑 -你去死...
- Funny. - Fuck you...
还有你骑来的那匹马
And the horse you rode in on.
还有你身后那票骑兵队
And the whole cavalry behind ya.
真好笑
Funny man.
那是我的工作
That's why I'm here.
再给他一杯酒
Give him another drink.
替我在里头撒尿
Piss in it for me.
我现在介绍的一位女士 做过全球巡回表演
I'm now gonna introduce a woman who's made a worldwide tour
一个让人讨厌的大牌明星
with top billing and all that other bullshit where they all hated her.
我要你们欢迎她
And I want you all to give her a warm welcome.
我知道你们办得到
I know you're all capable of it.
你们看来像一群毒虫
You look like a bunch of junkies.
她的名字是艾玛四十八
Her name is Emma 48's.
好啊!唱吧!
Oh, yeah! Go get it!
马克威饭店
计程车!
Taxi!
甜心...
Honey...
听着,我要出去一下
Listen, I'm gonna take a little walk.
我有几件事要办,好吗?
I got a couple of things I gotta take care of, all right?
-待会会见到你吗? -会的,来
- Will I see you later? - Yeah, here.
-拿着,我待会回家 -谢谢
- Take that, I'll be home later. - Thank you.
小心
Be careful.
嘿,你做什么?
Hey, what are you doin'?
乔伊
Joey.
乔伊,你为何不转身?
Come on, Joey. Why don't you turn around?
别这样,乔伊,转过来
Come on, Joey, turn around.
嘿,乔伊,别这样
Hey, Joey, come on.
乔伊?你干嘛这样?
Come on, Joey? What are you doin'?
好了,你干嘛那么生气?
Come on. What are you gettin' so angry about?
我们和好吧
Come on, be friends.
别这样,你是我弟弟
Come on, you're my brother.
-和好吧 -我是你弟弟?
- Be friends. - I'm your brother?
对,你这个混蛋 给我一个机会吧
Yeah, ya fuckin' bum. Give me a break, come on.
-亲我一下 -别这样好吗?
- Kiss me. - Come on, huh?
亲我一下嘛
Give me a kiss, come on.
等一下,我打电话叫家人来 你要不要他们看你亲我?
Wait, let me call my wife and kids. Don't you want them to see the kiss?
你要不要原谅我? 那么久以前的事了,忘了吧
You gonna forgive and forget? It's a long time ago, forget about it.
亲我一下就好
Just give me a kiss, come on.
好了
Come on.
你是我弟弟,好了
You're my brother. Come on.
好了,亲我一下
Come on, give me a kiss.
-什么? -好了
- What? - Come on.
-一切都好吗? -很好
- How's everything, all right? - Good.
-一切都好? -对
- Everything's all right? - Yeah.
-家人呢? -很好
- Family? - All right.
好了
Come on.
不要在这里这样,好了
You don't wanna do this here, come on.
我打电话给你 过两天我们聚一聚
Let me call you, we'll get together in a couple days.
-你会打给我? -我会的
- You'll call me? - I will.
不要忘了
Don't forget.
-我会打给你 -好
- I'll call you. - All right.
巴比松广场
杰克拉莫塔之夜
戏码有派迪查福斯,基罗德赛林
...光明正大地赢...
...won it legitimately...
莎士比亚,巴德舒伯,田纳西威廉
...没有人能剥夺,没有人
...and nobody could take that away from me, nobody.
有些人没那么幸运
Some people aren't that lucky.
像马龙白兰度 在“岸上风云”里演的角色
Like the one that Marlon Brando played in On the Waterfront,
一匹黑马现在走上穷途末路
an up-and-comer who's now a down-and-outer.
你记得他和他兄弟查理那个小贼
You remember that scene in the back of the car
在车子后座的那场戏吗?
with his brother Charley, a small-time racket guy?
那场的对白是这样的
And it went somethin' like this.
“不是他,查理,是你的错”
"It wasn't him, Charley, it was you.
“记得那晚在花园厅 你跑来我的更衣室”
"You remember that night at the Garden, you came to my dressing room
“你说：'小子,你今晚不能赢 我们把钱押在威尔森身上'”
"and you said, 'Kid, this ain't your night. We're goin' for the price on Wilson.'
“记得吗?'你今晚不能赢'”
"Remember that? 'This ain't your night.'
“我赢”
"My night.
“那天晚上我可以痛宰威尔森的”
"I could've taken Wilson apart that night.
“结果呢?”
"So, what happens?
“他在户外赛场赢得冠军 我得到什么?”
"He gets a title shot outdoors in the ballpark, and what do I get?
“立刻变成二流拳击手”
"A one-way ticket to palookaville.
“我那晚之后就一蹶不振,查理”
"I was never no good after that night, Charley.
“好像抵达巅峰,然后就只有下坡”
"It was like a peak you reach, and then it's downhill.
“都是因为你,查理”
"It was you, Charley.
“你是我哥哥”
"You was my brother.
“你应该照顾我一点的”
"You should've looked out for me a little bit.
“你应该多少照顾我一点的”
"You should've looked out for me just a little bit.
"You should've taken care of me just a little bit,
“不该为了一点钱而要我装死”
"instead of making me take them dives for the short-end money.
“你不明白”
"You don't understand.
“我本来可以有点格调 可以角逐冠军”
"I could've had class. I could've been a contender.
“我本来可能出名 而不是变成现在这样的废物”
"I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am.
“面对现实吧...是你的错,查理”
"Let's face it... it was you, Charley.
-“是你的错,查理” -你好吗,杰克?
- It was you, Charley." - How you doin', Jake?
-都没问题吧? -对
- Everything all right? - Yeah.
-准备好了? -你还有五分钟
- Ready? - You got about five minutes.
-你需要什么吗? -不用
- You need anything? - No.
你确定?
You sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
-外头有很多人? -对,挤满了
- A lot of people out there? - Yeah, it's crowded.
上场吧,冠军
Go get 'em, champ.
我是老大,我是老大...
I'm the boss, I'm the boss...
(腓利基人) 再一次地
召来那位眼瞎的人说:
“在神的面前说出真相 我们知道这个人是罪人”
“他到底是不是罪人 我不知道”那个人回答
“我只知道:我曾经眼瞎 现在我重见光明”
圣经约翰福音第九章24～26节
纪念海格曼努吉安老师
1916年5月23日～1980年5月26日 本着爱与决心的马丁